原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
翻译     吃冰棒  苏小黛  Margaery  elingbow
翻译     VioletCheng  不见脏话  CharlesZhang
翻译     kathy567  Carolgcz  王木木  Funky
翻译     盐湖凉开水  海云生  TracyOY  子V
时间轴   西·查  噃噃  Ans  没有影子
时间轴   caroline  紫夏  壬虚浪影
后期     渔夫
总监     布塔诚荐
我的房子
我的规则
我的咖啡
哈兰·斯隆贝
《火神之穴》
《一只小猪》  《针尖游戏》
哈兰·斯隆贝
早上好  斯隆贝先生
Morning, Mr. Thrombey.
斯隆贝先生  你在吗
Mr. Thrombey? You up there?
斯隆贝先生  我进来了
Mr. Thrombey, I'm coming in.
见鬼
Shit!
利刃出鞘
一周后
哈兰·斯隆贝去世
你杀了他  你这个混蛋
You killed him, you bastard!
你谋杀了他
You murdered him!
我没杀人
I didn't murder nobody!
你劈裂了他的脸
You slashed his face open.
让他躺在大街上血流如注
You left him bleeding in the street like a stuck pig,
然后你用一辆叉车碾碎了他的头
then you crushed his skull with a forklift
并烧掉了他的双手  毁掉了指纹
and burned his hands off to erase the fingerprints!
你无法证明
You'll never prove it.
我们有监控保姆摄像头的录像
We have the nanny-cam footage!
爱丽丝  把那个关了  好吗
Alice, turn that off now, please?
-你被捕了...  -为什么  就快完了
- You're under arrest for... - Why? It's almost over.
快点  拜托了  把它关了
Now. Please, just turn it off.
怎么了  他们快找出真凶了
What? They're finding out who did it
再说我房间的无线网信号不好
and the WiFi sucks in my room,
-别烦我了  -马上把它关掉
- so give me a break. - Turn it off, now.
-只剩两分钟了  -爱丽丝
- There's two minutes left. - Alice!
-凭什么  又没什么不好的东西  -关掉
- What? There isn't even anything bad on. - Off!
只是普通的电视剧
It's just normal TV
-他们只是在说话  -他们在说谋杀
- and they're just talking! - They're talking murder on it!
普通电视剧而已  他们只是在说话
Normal TV, and they're just talking!
你姐姐刚有个关系很好的朋友...
Your sister just had a friend she loved...
-行行行  随便吧  -割开了自己的喉咙
- Okay, okay! Okay! Whatever. - slit his throat open
她现在不应该听到这些
and she doesn't need to be hearing that right now!
注意一点
Let's be sensitive!
爱丽丝  你继续看你的剧  没事的
Alice, you can keep watching your show, it's fine.
-不了  反正我都猜到凶手了  -没事的
- No, I guessed who did it anyway. - It's okay.
抱歉  玛塔
I'm sorry, Marta.
没事
That's OK.
来电
沃尔特·斯隆贝
是哈兰的儿子
It's Harlan's son.
你好  沃尔特
Hi, Walt.
你好  玛塔  我是沃尔特
Hi, Marta, It's Walt.
你能早点来家里吗
Would you mind coming to the house early?
警察还要再询问一次所有人
The police have a few more questions for everybody.
什么
What?
不好意思  女士
Excuse me, ma'am.
你是佣人吗
You with the help?
她叫玛塔  她是爷爷的护士
Her name's Marta. She was Grandad's nurse.
她是跟我们一起的
She's with us.
"佣人"
"The help"?
没关系  不好意思
It's okay. I'm sorry.
不  有关系  搞什么鬼
No, it's not okay. What the hell?
你还好吗
How are you doing?
不是很好
Not very good.
很孤独
Alone.
经常这样  不知道接下来该怎么办
Lots of this and not knowing what to do next.
玛塔  有什么需要就说
Marta, anything you need...
你是这个家庭的一员
You're part of this family.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-你还好吗  孩子  -琳达
- How you doing, kiddo? - Linda.
你还好吗
How are you?
办葬礼有所帮助  至少能看到他
You know, the funeral helped, I guess. Just seeing him.
我觉得你应该来参加葬礼的
I thought you should have been there.
-但我少数不敌多数  -让警察来抓你吧
- I was outvoted. - Get arrested!
-我才不管你的死活呢  -理查德
- Die up your own ass for all I care! - Richard.
他不来
He's not coming.
兰森这个小混蛋
Ransom. Little shit.
葬礼也没来
Missed the funeral.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
你们可以开始了
Uh, we're ready for you now.
一个一个来
We'd like to see you one at a time.
好  我先去
All right. Uh, I'll go first.
希望这一切能在今晚的纪念仪式开始前
I'm assuming this will all be wrapped up
都结束
before the memorial tonight.
我们尽力  夫人
We'll do our best, ma'am.
那么...
So...
你还好吗  孩子
How you doing, kiddo?
现在我们重新正式自我介绍一下
We're just gonna reintroduce ourselves as a formality.
我是艾略特警督
I am Detective Lieutenant Elliot,
这位是瓦格纳警员
and this is Trooper Wagner.
现在  我会进行录音
Now, I'm going to record this,
斯隆贝
以便日后调查
just to make things easier.
好了  我们现在和琳达·德莱斯戴尔
All right, we're with Linda Drysdale
原姓斯隆贝
nee Thrombey,
琳达
哈兰·斯隆贝的长女在一起
Harlan Thrombey's eldest daughter,
讨论一周前被害人去世当晚
and discussing the events that took place
所发生的事
the night of his demise one week ago.
也就是11月8日
November eighth.
节哀顺变
We're very sorry for your loss.
谢谢  承蒙关心
Thank you. That means a lot.
我们知道那晚你们全家团聚
So, we understand on that night the family had gathered
给你父亲庆祝85岁生日
to celebrate your father's 85th birthday?
是的
Yes.
-办得如何  -派对吗
- How was it? - The party?
我爸死前那场吗
Pre-my-dad's-death?
挺好的
Oh, it was great.
有家庭成员以外的人参加吗
Did anyone besides the family show face?
弗兰  她是管家
Fran, the housekeeper.
他人不错  但毛发太浓密了
He was a nice guy, but he was so hairy.
-雅各布  -我跟意大利人约会过
- Jacob? - And I've dated Italian guys.
你懂我意思吗  就像...
You know what I mean? It was like...
玛塔  哈兰的看护
Marta, Harlan's caregiver.
是个乖女孩  工作很卖力
Good girl. Hard worker.
她家里来自厄瓜多尔
Her family's from Ecuador.
还有温娜塔
And Wanetta.
曾祖母  哈兰的妈妈
Great nana. Harlan's mom.
-你好  曾祖母  -他妈妈
- Hi, Nana. - His mom?
-曾祖母  -她多大年纪了
- Nana? - Wow. How old is she?
不知道
We have no idea.
好吧  还有你儿子  兰森
Okay, and your son, Ransom,
他也参加了吗
did he attend as well?
参加了  但很早就走了
Yes, but he left early.
兰森  你要走了吗
Ransom, are you leaving?
好的
Right, um...
你们三人差不多是同一时间抵达的
Would you say that all three of you showed up
可以这么说吗
around the same time?
不是
No.
理查德来得比较早  帮助承办方准备派对
Richard came early to help the caterers set up.
好的  你和你丈夫  理查德
Okay. And you and your husband, Richard,
是在波士顿一家房地产公司上班吗
work at a real estate firm in Boston?
不是  那...那是我的公司
No. It's... It's my company.
对  对  抱歉
Right. Right. Sorry.
我白手起家成立了自己的公司
I built my business from the ground up.
就像你父亲一样
Oh, just like your father.
你们关系非常好
You two were very close.
我们俩有专属的秘密沟通方式
We... We had our own secret way of communicating.
每个人都会有和爸爸相处的秘诀
I mean, you had to find that with dad.
得有个可以跟他一起玩的游戏
You had to find a game to play with him,
要是你找到了  并且遵守他的规则...
and if you did that, and you played by his rules...
理查德
爸爸是每个人心中的偶像  不是吗
Everyone idolizes their dad, right?
我不知道  是吗
I don't know. Do they?
也不尽然
Very much not.
不知道我刚刚为什么这么说
Don't know why I said that.
但我妻子  琳达  就是这样
But my wife, Linda, does.
哈兰用一部生锈的打字机开始了写作
Harlan started out with a rusty Smith Corona
最终成为了
and built himself into
史上最畅销的推理小说作家之一
one of the best-selling mystery writers of all time.
他的孩子们似乎也都白手起家  功成名就
Seems like all his kids are self-made overachievers.
当然
Sure.
在此声明  与我对话的是沃尔特·斯隆贝
For the record, I'm speaking with Walt Thrombey,
沃尔特
哈兰·斯隆贝最小的儿子
Harlan Thrombey's youngest son.
你父亲的出版公司是你在经营吗
So, you run your father's publishing company?
是的  这是我的...我们的...
Yeah. It's my... It's our...
是家族的出版公司
It's the family's publishing company.
爸爸信任我的经营能力
Dad trusts me to run it.
三十种语言
Thirty languages.
总销量超过八千万本  真正地泽被后世
Over 80 million copies sold. A real legacy.
你们是他的书迷吗
You guys fans?
我不是很爱看小说  但是...
I mean, I don't do much fiction reading myself, but...
忠实书迷  我是他的忠实书迷
Big fan. I'm a big fan.
他笔下的情节就像...
I mean, his plots are just like...
我就不给你剧透了  但是...
Like, I won't spoil it for you but...
就比如《千支利刃》
Okay, like Thousand Knives?
还有《奶牛和猎枪》
The Cow and the Shotgun?
这些情节都是怎么想出来的
Like, where do you come up with that?
爸爸说这些情节
Well, dad said the plots just
都是完整地从他脑中蹦出来的
popped into his head, fully formed.
这对他来说很容易
It was the easy part for him.
你当晚也在场  对吗
So you're in the area, right?
你们可能都是差不多时间到的
You guys probably arrived around the same time.
我们都是八点左右到的
We all got here around 8:00.
我妻子  唐娜  她是我的主心骨
My wife, Donna, she's my rock.
我的天  唐娜  你没事吧
Jesus, Donna! Are you all right?
我儿子  雅各布  十六岁
My son, Jacob, he's 16.
在政治方面非常活跃
Very politically active.
那孩子就是个不折不扣的纳粹
The boy is literally a Nazi.
他就是个另类右派键盘侠
He's an alt-right troll dipshit.
现在的孩子有了互联网  都非同小可
Kids today with the Internet, it's amazing.
所以那晚一切都挺好的
So the night went well?
我们当然都很伤心  但是
I mean, we're all gutted, but,
我很高兴能跟他一起度过那样一晚
I was happy to have that night with him.
能陪在他身边  回想我们的书
To be by his side. To think about our books
以及我们凭借它们赢得的一切
and what we've accomplished with them.
我仿佛还能感觉到他的手放在我的肩膀上
It's like I can still feel his hand on my shoulder.
把他的火炬传承给我
Passing the torch.
现在这位是琼妮·斯隆贝
So, we're here with Joni Thrombey,
琼妮
哈兰·斯隆贝的儿媳
Harlan Thrombey's daughter-in-law?
是的  我嫁给了他儿子  尼尔
Yeah, I married his son, Neil.
我们有一个女儿  梅格
We had one daughter, Meg.
后来  尼尔十五年前去世了
And then Neil passed on 15 years ago.
但你仍然跟斯隆贝家的人很亲近
But you remained close to the Thrombeys?
他们就是我的家人
They're my family.
他们既让我感到自由
I feel simultaneously freed by
又让我感到被支持着
and supported by them.
这种对立的平衡正是弗拉姆的可贵之处
It's that balance of opposites that's the nugget of Flam.
抱歉  什么的可贵之处...
Sorry, the nugget of...
弗拉姆
Flam.
想起来了  弗拉姆  你的护肤公司  抱歉
Yeah, Flam, your skincare company. Sorry.
我原谅你了
I forgive you.
是的  是做护肤的
Yeah, it's skincare,
但它推崇的是一整套生活方式
but it promotes a total lifestyle.
通过承认自身需求来自给自足
Self-sufficiency with an acknowledgement of human need.
这就是弗拉姆
That's Flam.
但它也是哈兰的理念
But it's also Harlan.
他帮我和梅格撑过了一些很艰难的日子
He got me and Meg through some tough times.
爷爷按年给我妈生活费
Grandad gives my mom a yearly allowance
梅格
而且他从来没有忘记
and he's never missed wiring
帮我把学费汇给学校
a tuition payment to my schools.
他是个非常无私的人
He's a genuinely selfless man.
但你却提前离开了派对
But you left the party early?
好好玩
Have fun.
去史密斯那里见几个朋友
To see some friends at Smith.
你知道爸爸出钱供她念什么
You know dad pays for her
秘密马克思主义后解构
crypto-Marxist-post-deconstructural-
女权诗歌理论什么的专业吗
feminist-poetry-theory-whatever major?
她明明可以留下来吃完蛋糕再走的
She could have stuck around for the cake.
我觉得琳达不太高兴
I think Linda was upset.
但哈兰很理解
But Harlan understood.
好吧
Right.
你俩差不多是同一时间出现在派对上的
You two showed up to the party around the same time...
能暂停一下吗
If I could pause?
我实在...
Because I just...
那人到底是谁啊
Who is that guy?
而且为什么又要这样再来一次
And why are we doing all this again?
只是一些后续提问
This is just some follow-up questions.
我们想调查得彻底些
Um, we're attempting to be thorough,
好查明死因
so we can figure out the manner of death.
你说"死因"  意思是可能是有人杀了他
So by "manner of death," you mean if someone killed him?
可能是我们中的一个杀了他
If one of us killed him?
-他的某个家人杀了他  -不  沃尔特  不
- One of his family killed him? - No, no, Walt, Walt, no, no...
你是那个意思吗  警督
Is that what you're suggesting, Lieutenant?
没人那么说  好吗
No one's saying that, okay?
这都是例行公事
This is all pro-forma.
好吧
Okay.
所以那人他妈是谁
So who the fuck is that?
这位是贝努瓦·布兰克
This is Benoit Blanc.
-贝努瓦·布兰克  -是的
- Benoit Blanc? - Yes.
布兰克先生是位颇负盛名的私家侦探
Mr. Blanc is a private investigator of great renown.
等等
Wait a minute.
我在推特上看过《纽约客》关于你的一篇文章
I read a tweet about a New Yorker article about you.
《最后一位绅士侦探》
"The Last of the Gentlemen Sleuths."
你破了网球冠军那个案子
You solved that case with the tennis champ?
你很有名
You're famous.
布兰克先生不是警局的人
Mr. Blanc is not with the police department
也没有正式参与这个案子
and not officially involved in the case,
但他会作为顾问提供意见
but he's offered to consult.
我很荣幸  我也可以为他担保
Now, I happily obliged, and I can vouch for him.
布兰克先生  我知道你是谁
Mr. Blanc, I know who you are.
我在《纽约客》上读过你的简介
I read your profile in the New Yorker.
我非常喜欢
I found it delightful.
我刚埋葬了我85岁的父亲
I just buried my 85-year-old father
他是自杀身亡的
who committed suicide.
你所来为何
Why are you here?
我是受一名客户的委托而来的
I'm here at the behest of a client.
谁
Who?
恕难奉告
I cannot say.
但我可以向你保证
But let me assure you this.
我在这里只是个装饰
My presence will be ornamental.
你将发现我是个心怀敬意的
You will find me a respectful,
安静的  被动的
quiet, passive observer
真相观察者
of the truth.
好吧
Fine.
那找到真相了吗
Are we getting there?
快了
Nearly.
哈兰的护士  她也出席了派对
Harlan's nurse, she was at the party
是为了提供专业服务吗
in a professional capacity?
玛塔
Marta?
应该是吧
I guess.
哈兰雇她待在身边
Harlan hired her to be around to take care
以应对各种医疗需求
of whatever medical needs popped up.
但说实话  她就像我们家的一员
But really, she's like part of the family.
她是个好女孩
Good kid.
也成了哈兰的好友
Been a good friend to Harlan.
家里是从巴拉圭来的
Family's from Paraguay.
琳达非常赞赏她的职业操守
Linda really likes her work ethic.
"我们移民  干活很靠谱"
"Immigrants. We get the job done."
-我...  -音乐剧《汉密尔顿》里的
- I... - From Hamilton.
《汉密尔顿》啊
Oh, Hamilton.
太棒了  真棒
It's so good. It's so good.
我在纽约公共剧院看的
I saw it at The Public.
我能不能...
May I just, um...
我马上就消失  但在此之前
Then I'll recede, but...
我自己也是白手起家
As a self-made man myself,
我必须表达我的钦佩之情
I have to express my admiration
你如此稳扎稳打地追随你父亲的脚步
for how you followed in your father's footsteps.
-谢谢  -太棒了
- Thank you. - Just marvelous.
你们整个家族都是
You know, the whole family, too.
琼妮有她的事业
And Joni with her thing,
沃尔特有他的出版帝国
and Walt with his publishing empire...
真是...
It's...
这个嘛
Well...
当然  沃尔特做得很好
Yes, I mean, Walt, he's done well
毕竟有爸爸给他的资源
with what dad gave him.
当然这不重要
Not that it matters.
但说真的  爸爸每年给他两本书
But really, dad hands him a book twice a year
而沃尔特就拿去出版
and Walt publishes it.
我跟他可不太一样
It's just not the same.
但沃尔特肯定还经营周边产品  改编权
But surely Walt runs the merchandising, adaptations,
影视化版权...
film and television rights, I mean...
你是在套我的话吗  侦探
Are you baiting me, Detective?
你明知道他根本没做那些
You know he doesn't.
如果你觉得我蠢到
And if you think I am dumb enough
能被人套出关于家族生意的话
to be baited into talking family business,
或者我弟弟的坏话
into shit-talking my baby brother,
而且是在一个警探
in front of a police detective,
和一个警员面前...
and a state trooper...
沃尔特什么都不经营
Walt doesn't run shit.
因为根本就没有什么影视化版权
Because there are no TV and film rights.
哈兰从不允许对他的书进行任何改编
Harlan never allowed any adaptations of his books.
他不喜欢这想法
Hated the idea.
不会吧
No.
真的
Yeah!
让沃尔特很抓狂
Drives Walt nuts.
因为那才是真正赚钱的部分
'Cause that's where the real money is.
每当沃尔特借酒壮胆
When Walt would get a little Irish courage in him,
他就会去纠缠哈兰
he'd get into it with Harlan.
他在派对上有"纠缠"吗
Did he "get into it" at the party?
我的天
Oh, my God!
拜托  爸
Come on, Dad!
他根本不肯让他清闲  可怜的家伙
Wouldn't leave him alone, the poor guy.
网飞那些人  他们的商务代表...
The Netflix guys, their business affair guy...
哈兰最终不得不炒了他
Harlan finally had to give him the hook.
我没听到他具体说了什么
I didn't hear what he said,
但他肯定是把他踢出局了
but he must've really handed him his lunch.
因为沃尔特后面整晚都像只受伤的小狗一样
'Cause Walt was like a wounded puppy the rest of the night.
什么  理查德说了什么
What? Richard said what?
不  天啊  我们没有"纠缠"
No. Jesus. We did not get "into it."
我只是想有个准确的画面
I'm just trying to get an accurate impression.
哈兰在派对上把你叫到了一旁
Harlan took you aside at the party.
你回来后懊悔至极
When you returned, you were chastened.
哈兰到底对你说了什么
What did Harlan say to you?
网飞那些人  他们的商务代表
The Netflix guys, their business affair guy.
他送了点东西过来  这次的开价不错
He sent something over. It's hard numbers this time,
我觉得过了这个村
and I just think this is a window
就没这个店了
that's not gonna stay open.
我们要牢牢抓住
We need to take advantage of it
你只要看看价钱就好
and then you just need to look at the numbers!
-是  沃尔特...  -爸  爸
- Yeah, Walt, look... - Dad! Dad!
是你让我负责我们的书
You... You put me in charge of our books.
就让我做主  让我做这个吧  求你了
Let me be in charge! Let me do this! Please!
儿子  那不是我们的书
They're not our books, son.
是我的书
They're my books.
我也不希望我们谈着谈着就吵起来
And this is not how I wanted to have this conversation.
但是你说得对  很对
But you're right, you're right.
我栓着你做不该你管的事情
It's unfair of me to keep you tethered
是不公平的
to something that isn't yours to control.
什么
What?
对  我严重地伤害了你
No, I've done you a grave disservice.
这么多年来
All these years,
我一直阻碍了你
I've kept you from building something
建立属于自己的事业
of your own that was yours.
但是你很快就不再负责
But you're not going to be running
出版社的业务了
the publishing house anymore.
你自由了
You're free of it.
爸  你是把我给炒了吗
Dad, are you firing me?
不
No...
我们明天再谈细节
We'll talk details tomorrow.
我心意已决
My mind's made up.
好孩子
Good boy.
我们谈了谈  关于电子书业务
We talked. We had a business discussion about e-books.
天啊  没什么
Jesus. It was nothing.
你要是说吵架的话
You want to talk about an argument,
兰森跟他吵了一架
hell, Ransom had an argument with him.
兰森  就是
Ransom, that's, uh,
理查德和琳达的儿子
Richard and Linda's son?
我们都爱兰森  他是个好孩子  我们爱他
Look, we all love Ransom, he's a good kid. We love him.
但是
But?
但他一直都是家里的害群之马
But he's always been the black sheep of the family.
我不是想...
And I'm not trying to...
通常而言  家丑不可外扬
I like to keep stuff like this in the family.
但是兰森  他从来不工作
But with Ransom, he's never had a job.
而我爸  不知道为什么
And Dad, for some unknown reason,
还一直养着他
always supported him.
他们之间爱恨交加  总吵架
They have this love-hate bond. They fight.
但是那天晚上  天啊  吵翻天了
But that night, God, they had a blowout.
因为什么
About what?
你是不是疯了
Are you goddamn insane?
猜不出来是什么  但是很激烈
Couldn't make it out really, but it was huge.
奇怪的是  他们是去另外一个房间吵的
And it's strange they went into another room to do it.
通常他们就喜欢当着全家人的面
Usually they like to stoke up drama
针锋相对
in front of the whole family.
说到"纠缠"
Speaking of getting into it...
你提前抵达了  帮忙准备派对  你...
You were at the house early, to help the caterers set up. Did...
你当时跟哈兰有过谈话吗
Did you converse with Harlan at that time?
他在场  我们肯定说过话
Well, he was there. We must have spoke.
在他的书房里呢
In his study?
没有
I don't think so.
我今天早晨问过承办人
You see, I spoke with the caterer this morning,
她没看见你帮她的员工
she didn't see you helping her staff.
倒是听到哈兰那天下午
She did hear Harlan in a screaming match
跟人在书房里吵了一架
with somebody that afternoon in his study.
是的  我不...
Yeah, I don't...
吵了一架
Screaming match?
不
No.
但是琼妮也在
But Joni was here, too.
她来得早  可能是跟她
She was early, so it might have been her.
你们可以问问她
You can maybe ask her.
是两个男人的声音
These were two male voices.
哈兰喊道
Harlan shouted the phrase...
你去告诉她  不然我亲自去
You tell her or I will!
"你去告诉她
"You tell her
不然我亲自去"
or I will!"
想起来了吗
Bells ringing?
这不关你的事
That's none of your business.
你别插手我的婚姻
You stay out of my marriage.
我了解我女儿  她会想要知道的
I know my daughter, and she would want to know.
我已经都写在这封给她的信里了
I've put all of it in this letter to her.
明天  她就能看到
Tomorrow, she gets it.
哈兰  我警告你
Harlan, I'm warning you.
-不  她有权知道  -别插手我的婚姻
- No, she deserves to know. - You stay out of my marriage.
她有权知道  你来告诉她
She deserves to know, and you're gonna tell her.
-我绝不  -你去告诉她  不然我亲自去
- The hell I am! - You tell her or I will!
是的  我知道
Yes. I know.
是的
Yes.
哈兰终于下定决心要把他妈妈送到养老院
Harlan had finally decided to put his mom in a nursing home
琳达一直都反对这事
and Linda had always opposed that.
我想要等到
And I wanted to wait until we got back
我们回到波士顿再告诉琳达
to Boston, uh, to tell Linda,
免得大闹一场
so, to avoid a whole scene,
但是哈兰想让我当时就告诉她
and Harlan wanted me to tell her then.
就这事
That was it.
对不起  忘了
Sorry. Forgot.
房子
The house?
到得早  理查德说你在场
Early. Richard said you were there.
我确实来得早
I was at the house early.
为了见哈兰
To see Harlan?
To see Harlan.
是的
Yes.
你找哈兰什么事
What were you seeing Harlan about?
关于梅格的学费
It was just a mix-up with the, uh,
付款方面出了差错
the payment for Meg's tuition.
我...  我...
I'm... I'm...
抱歉我要问细点
I'm sorry to press,
究竟是什么差错呢
but what kind of mix-up?
学校还没收到支票
Yeah, the school hasn't got the check yet.
我不知道艾伦为什么没寄出
I don't know why Alan didn't mail it.
艾伦没寄出
Well, Alan didn't mail it
是因为他发现有出入
because he caught a discrepancy.
艾伦的办公室一直都是按你的要求
Alan's office has been wiring tuition directly to the school
把学费直接汇给学校的
as per your request.
但是负责你每年生活费的菲利斯办公室
But Phyllis's office that handles your yearly allowance
也一直都在直接给你汇学费款
has been wiring tuition monies directly to you as well.
你一直都收着双份的梅格学费
You have been double-dipping Meg's tuition
从我这偷钱
and stealing from me.
每年十万
$100,000 a year,
偷了四年
for the past four years.
哈兰  我不知道怎么会出这种差错
Harlan, I don't know how this mix-up happened,
-但我发誓  -现在我给你开这张学费支票
- but I swear to God... - So, now I am writing this tuition check,
但是你要知道  这是你和梅格
but you must know that this is the last money
从我这拿到的最后一笔钱了
you or Meg will get from me.
别这样  你不了解...
Please, you don't understand...
琼妮  我知道你会难受
Joni, I know it'll hurt,
但这都是为了你们好
but it's all for the best.
我心意已决
My mind's made up.
是跟学校办公室之间
It was, uh, a money wiring issue
汇款出了差错
with the office at the school.
所以我让哈兰为这学期的学费开张支票
So I had to ask Harlan to cut a check for the semester.
没什么大事
No big deal.
好吧
Well...
我们还是
Why don't we, uh,
先休息一下  然后再...
just take a little break and we'll resu...
不...
Oh, no...
她走了
She's gone.
理查德
Richard!
琼妮  你见到理查德了吗
Joni, have you seen Richard?
没有  警察刚问完我
No, I was, uh, just done with the, um...
好的  谢谢
Okay, thanks.
没见到
No.
该死  理查德
Damn it. Richard!
理查德
Richard?
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
可能我期望过高了
See, I might be a victim of my own expectation here,
但是当大名鼎鼎的贝努瓦·布兰克
but when the great Benoit Blanc
来敲我门的时候
comes knocking at my door,
我就期待着能有什么
I expect it's going to be about something,
就算不离奇
if not extraordinary,
至少也是有趣的事
then at least interesting.
但是  恕我直言
But... I'm sorry,
这明摆着是一起自杀案
this is an open-and-shut case of suicide
说实话  贝尼  我们得谈谈
and, uh, quite frankly, Benny, we're getting to the point
我们究竟是在干什么
where I need to know what we're doing here.
自杀方式
The method?
割喉
Throat slit?
是典型的自杀方式吗
Typical for a suicide?
是  我知道  是有点夸张
Yes, I mean, that's dramatic.
但是你看看周围
But look around.
老爷子简直是活在推理游戏中
I mean, the guy practically lives in a Clue board.
拜托  贝尼  跟我说说行吗
Come on, Benny, talk to me, all right?
你让我把所有人请回来
Now, you tell me to invite all of these people back
再问一遍  我懂
for questioning all over again. I get it.
我已经派人在这个郡
Listen, I've had boots on the ground
巡逻了好一阵了
in this county for a while now.
大家都跟表面上看起来差不多
People are generally what they seem to be.
凶手不在这家人中
You're not gonna find murderers in this family.
这家人家庭和睦
This is a pleasant family
偶尔争吵
with the usual quarrels,
但是没有杀人动机
but no possible motives for murder.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
哈兰·斯隆贝的护士  玛塔...
Harlan Thrombey's nurse. Marta...
-卡布瑞拉  -玛塔·卡布瑞拉
- Cabrera. - Marta Cabrera.
-卡布瑞拉小姐  请在里面等  -这边请
- Miss Cabrera, you can just wait inside... - Please.
-我们很快就...  -卡布瑞拉小姐
- and we'll be with you in... - Miss Cabrera.
我做了一点调查
I've been doin' a little pokin'.
你是一名注册护士
You were hired on a part-time basis
在这里兼职  对吗
as a registered nurse, yes?
是的  我没有加入家访护士协会
Yes. I don't work for a VNA.
直接受雇于哈兰
Harlan hired me directly.
请坐吧
Take a seat, please.
你拿的是固定工资
And you're paid a flat rate
一周工作几小时
for how many hours a week?
最初每周十五小时  后来他...
Well, I started at 15, and then he...
他需要更多帮助
He needed more help.
医疗方面的吗
Medical help?
他需要一个朋友
He needed a friend.
有善心就能成为好护士吗
Does having a kind heart make you a good nurse?
好了  布兰克  你不能...
All right, Blanc, I mean, this is...
知道了  玛塔  我们刚说到
Yeah, yeah. Marta? We were just discussing
家庭成员是否有杀人动机
possible motives in the family.
我猜哈兰应该会对你坦言
I suspect that Harlan has told you
每个人的真实情况
much unfiltered truth about each of 'em.
根据我所掌握的信息
And a little bird has told me,
该怎么委婉地表达呢
how shall I put this delicately...
说谎会使你产生
You have a regurgitative reaction
反胃反应
to mistruthin'.
谁告诉你的
Who told you that?
是真的吗
Is it true?
是的
Yes.
我从小就这样
It's something I've had since I was a kid.
是生理反应
It's a physical thing that I...
一想到说谎
Just the thought of lying...
我就会呕吐
Yeah, it makes me puke.
真的吗
Really?
理查德是不是出轨了
Is Richard havin' an affair?
男人为什么总是
Why do men instinctively
本能地自寻死路
pull at loose threads on their parachutes?
什么
What?
理查德
Richard?
-出轨  -对
- An affair? - Yeah.
只要回答是或不是就行
A yes or no will do.
不是
No.
我去
Shit!
-天啊  -姑娘  抱歉
- Oh, my god! - Dear girl, I'm sorry.
我以为你只是比喻
I assumed you were speaking figuratively.
-我车上有湿巾  -好了  给你
- I have Wet-Naps in the car. - All right, here, here.
喝口水
Just take a sip of this.
拿着
Take that.
不可思议
That's quite somethin'.
-谢谢  -但我显然猜对了
- Thanks. - But I was obviously right.
理查德确实出轨了
Richard is having an affair.
他的岳父发现后当面与他对峙
His father-in-law found out and confronted him.
"你去告诉她  不然我亲自去"
"You tell her or I will."
好  就算是这样  他...
Okay, but even if that were the case, he...
你还好吗
You all right?
-我没事  -就算是这样
- Yeah. - Even if that were the case, I mean,
为了防止出轨被曝光而起杀心
protecting a relationship as a motive,
这动机不够充分  你应该清楚
that's weak sauce. You know that.
还有琼妮
Well, then there is Joni.
-琼妮  -琼妮
- Joni? - Joni?
养生大师琼妮
Lifestyle guru Joni?
不可能  哈兰在资助她们母女
No, Harlan was supporting her and her daughter
她们不可能想让他死
and that's the opposite of a motive.
那如果资助有中断的风险...
And if that support was threatened...
卡布瑞拉小姐  请稍等
Miss Cabrera, one moment, please.
我只是想去漱漱口
Yes, I just wanna get some Scope.
卡布瑞拉小姐
Miss Cabrera...
哈兰是不是打算中断琼妮的生活费
Was Harlan plannin' on cutting off Joni's allowance?
琼妮啊
Oh, Joni.
怎么了
What's up?
我的天
Oh, my God.
如果你又想吐
All right, don't answer that
就别回答了  拜托
if you're gonna puke again, please.
梅格说他是直接向学校汇款的
Meg said he paid the school directly.
琼妮说他是把钱汇给自己的
Joni said he sent the money to her.
两人说的都是真话
Both were true.
她私吞了第二笔钱
She was pocketing the double payment.
哈兰发现后
Harlan found out,
就一分也不给她了
and cut her off without a cent.
对吗
Yes?
所以她就为了分得遗产把他杀了
So she bumps him off for the inheritance?
得了吧  你看过她的社交媒体主页吗
Come on, no, have you seen her Insta?
她是网络红人
She's an influencer.
对  为了生活费而杀人
No, allowance as a motive?
这同样说不通
Again, more weak sauce.
你给出的动机都不够强烈
You're just dumpin' that vat of weak sauce on me.
同意  但她说谎了
Granted. But she lied to me.
他们三个都说谎了
All three of them did.
三个
Three?
沃尔特
Walter.
我明白你的意思了
I see where you're going with this.
哈兰之前就拒绝过沃尔特出售影视化版权
Harlan had turned Walter down before regarding film rights,
但那天晚上  哈兰又说了什么话刺激了他
but that night, somethin' Harlan said shook him.
看看他的行为模式
Now we look at the pattern.
哈兰在清理门户
Harlan was cleanin' house.
怪不得
No wonder.
他是不是准备开除沃尔特
Did he plan to fire Walter?
我能不能在里面等
Can I just wait inside?
我好像不应该待在这里
I feel like I shouldn't be here.
好  请在里面等吧
Yeah, please, just wait inside.
别走太远  好吗
Stay close, all right?
你很有耐心  我的朋友
You have been very patient, my friend.
是的
And yes,
你说得对
you are right.
不论是薄弱的不在场证明还是家庭纷争
None of these weak alibis and domestic squibbles
都无法回答你的问题
answer your question...
"贝努瓦·布兰克为什么会来"
"Why is Benoit Blanc here?"
我来告诉你原因
Well, now I will tell you why.
我来这里是因为今天早上
I'm here because this mornin',
有人回避了一个非常重要的问题
someone dodged a very important question.
谁
Who?
我
Me.
琳达问我是受谁委托
Linda asked who hired me.
你是受谁委托
Well, who hired you?
我不知道
I do not know.
昨天我收到了一个装满现金的信封
An envelope of cash showed up at my apartment yesterday
和斯隆贝死讯的新闻剪报
with a news clippin' of Thrombey's death.
一个信封就把你招来了
An envelope? That worked?
装满现金的信封
An envelope of cash.
这就说明有人怀疑其中有鬼
So somebody suspects foul play
费尽心思隐瞒身份
and goes through this ha cha dance of hiring me,
雇我查案
of staying anonymous.
这根本说不通
It makes no damn sense.
却让我无法抗拒
Compels me, though.
再说一遍案发时
Walk me through everyone's whereabouts
每个人的行踪
at the time of death.
派对结束时大约是十一点半
We know that the party ended around 11:30.
-晚安  琼妮  -晚安
- Good night, Joni. - 'Night.
玛塔陪哈兰上楼
Marta took Harlan upstairs
帮他注射药物
to give him his meds.
通向哈兰卧室和阁楼办公室的楼梯
The stairs leading up to Harlan's bedroom
踩上去会发出很响的吱嘎声
and his attic office creak horribly
而琳达睡觉很浅
and Linda is a light sleeper.
所以我们掌握了
So we know every time
当晚所有上下楼梯的记录
someone took the stairs that night.
第一次是琼妮听到
The first was when Joni heard a ka-thunk
楼上某个地方发出"咣当"一声
from somewhere above her in the house.
她担心哈兰
She's concerned about Harlan,
所以上楼查看情况
so she goes up to investigate...
吵醒了琳达
Waking Linda.
哈兰和玛塔在阁楼办公室
Harlan was in his attic office with Marta.
-你好  琼妮  -我好像...你好
- Hi, Joni. - I thought... Hi.
他解释说他们刚刚把围棋棋盘打翻了
He explained that they had just knocked over the Go board.
我刚刚打翻了围棋棋盘  所以...
I just knocked over the Go board, so...
就是格子棋盘石头棋子的那种棋
You know, that game with the grid and stones?
他们每晚都会下
They play it every night.
他没事  "回去睡吧"
He was fine. "Go to bed."
回去睡吧  琼妮
Go to bed, Joni.
-爱你  晚安  -爱你
- Love you. 'Night. - Love you.
-于是她照做了  -再见
- So she did. - Bye.
十分钟后
Ten minutes later,
琳达再次被吵醒
Linda is awoken a second time...
玛塔离开了
By Marta leaving.
沃尔特  我走了
Walt, I'm leaving.
沃尔特在门廊抽雪茄  他儿子也在
Walt was smokin' a cigar on the porch with his son.
他看到她出门  开车离开
He saw her leave and drive off.
他看了下时间
Noted the time.
是午夜
Midnight.
十五分钟后
Fifteen minutes later,
琳达第三次也是最后一次被吵醒
Linda is awoken for the third and final time...
是有人下楼梯
By someone coming down the stairs.
是哈兰  下楼吃夜宵
Harlan, who came down for a midnight snack.
爸爸  回去睡觉
Dad, go back to bed.
沃尔特试图劝阻他
Which Walt tried to discourage.
基于以上事实
Based on this,
法医判定死亡时间
the medical examiner determined the time of death
在凌晨十二点一刻和两点之间
to be between 12:15 and 2.00 a.m.
沃尔特十二点半左右抽完雪茄  梅格回家了
As Walt was finishing his cigar at about 12:30, Meg came home.
她直接回房间睡觉了
She went straight to bed.
沃尔特和雅各布很快也回去睡觉了
Walt and Jacob turned in shortly after that.
那天夜里晚些时候
And sometime later that night,
时间不确定  但可能是凌晨三点左右
it's undetermined, but possibly near 3:00 a.m.,
梅格被外面的狗叫声吵醒
Meg woke up because the dogs were barking outside.
她上了洗手间  又继续睡了
She used the bathroom, went back to bed.
就是这样
That's it. All right?
每个人的说法都吻合
Now, everyone's stories matched,
每个时间点都能对应
every moment accounted for.
没有其他楼梯通往哈兰的房间吗
And there is no other staircase up to Harlan's room?
没有  就那个嘎吱响的
None. Just the creaky one.
有意思
Interesting.
我们知道不是兰森干的
So, we know that Ransom didn't do it
因为他不在场
because he wasn't there.
玛塔也不可能
Marta couldn't have.
她离开时哈兰还活着
Harlan was still alive when she left.
-没错  -梅格
- Yeah. - Meg...
梅格在死亡时间段内
Meg came home during the window
-回家的  不是吗  -听着  这...
- of the time of death, right? - Now look, look, it was a...
但这确实是自杀  好吗
Except it was a suicide, all right?
哈兰割开了自己的颈动脉
Harlan slit right through his carotid.
我们看到血迹喷溅形态完全未遇阻挡
We saw from the blood splat patterns that they were uninterrupted,
意味着当时几乎不可能
meaning, it's almost impossible for anyone
有人在他身旁
to have been around him at the time.
是他自己割了喉  好吗
He's the one who cut his own throat, all right?
我不明白为什么还要一遍遍调查
I don't know why we keep goin' over this.
物证推断出的案情也可能是完全错误的
Physical evidence can tell a clear story with a forked tongue.
-什么  -从今天早上的情况可以看到
- What?  - And as we can see from this mornin',
每个人都会撒谎
everyone can lie.
几乎每个人
Well, almost everyone.
卡布瑞拉小姐
Miss Cabrera...
我们让你等了一下午
We kept you waiting all afternoon,
是因为我想听你最后一个说
because I wanted to hear from you last.
我需要在脑海中构建那晚完整的故事线
I needed an entire picture of the evening in my head,
而你那部分是其中最关键的
and your piece of it is at its very center.
所以不着急  慢慢讲
So, please take your time.
你十一点半送斯隆贝先生上楼
You took Mr. Thrombey upstairs at 11:30
并于午夜离开
and left at midnight.
仔细回想
Think very carefully
越详细越好
and with as much detail as possible.
告诉我们那半个小时里发生了什么
Tell us what happened in that half hour?
-上上上  我可以  -你可以吗
- Up, up, up, I got it. - Yeah, you got it?
上上上  我可以  上上上  我可以
Up, up, up, I got it. Up, up, up, I got it.
-上上上  我可以  -好的
- Up, up, up, I got it. - Okay, that's...
哈兰
Harlan...
-上上上  我可以  -我们...
- Up, up, up, I got it. - Let's...
上上上  我可以
Up, up, up, I got it.
-好了  -不要犹豫
- Okay. - No second thoughts.
不  不  不不不
No. No, no, no, no.
-上来  -我喝了一杯香槟
- Get up here! - I had a glass of champagne.
-哈兰  听我说  -我们...
- Harlan, listen to me. - We are...
-很晚了  我喝了...  -你只喝了一杯
- It's late. I had... - You've only had one glass.
-没错  一杯香槟  我不能  -我们不能
- Exactly. A glass of champagne. I don't... - We are not breaking
在我生日这天打破传统
tradition on my birthday!
你能快点用药然后去睡觉吗
Can you just take your goddamn medicine and go to bed?
如果你想把那瓶破药注入我体内
If you're gonna put that vile shit in me,
就得付出努力
you have to earn it.
今天是我生日
On my birthday.
-老天  -85岁生日
- Oh, God. - Eighty-fifth birthday.
-好吧  天啊  -我这么老了
- Fine. Jesus! - I'm so old.
-我这么老了  -你是真喜欢搞事情啊
- I'm so old. - You really love drama, huh?
玛塔
Marta.
来吧  用九乘九的格子
Okay, let's do this. Nine-by-nine.
-好  -你准备好了吗
- Right. - You ready?
-我会吊打你  -你确定吗
- I'll whip your ass. - Are you sure?
当然  当然
Yeah. Yeah.
口气挺大
How dare you.
我知道结局会如何
I know how this is gonna end.
这是什么路数
What is that?
为什么我下围棋总赢不了你你
Why can't I beat you at this game?
因为我下棋不是为了赢你
Because I'm not playing to beat you.
我是要摆出美丽图案
I'm playing to build a beautiful pattern.
你这是虐待老人
That's elder abuse.
我要打给退休人员协会
I'm gonna call the AARP.
别让我拿皮带捆你  老爷爷
Don't make me get the belt, abuelo.
基本已经输了
It's basically over.
我唯一的希望就是地震来袭
My only hope is that an earthquake will strike.
但这有多大可能呢
But what are the chances?
来人
Hello?
来人  来人
Hello? Hello?
有人吗  快躲门框下
Hello? Get under a door frame!
棒
Yes!
你真是输不起  打针然后睡觉去
Such a bad loser you are! Meds, then bed.
我受够你了
I'm done with you.
行吧
That's fair.
沃尔特在外面门廊吸他那恶心的雪茄
Walt is smoking that filthy cigar out there on the porch.
恶心还致死的玩意
Dead and nasty things.
今晚过得怎么样
How was tonight?
今晚还好
Tonight was good.
是吗
Yeah?
我知道你并不期待今晚
I know you weren't looking forward to it.
确实  但我做到了
No. But I did it.
我断了他们四个人的钱
I cut the line on all four of 'em.
是的
Yeah.
并不容易
Wasn't easy.
这该死的财富
This goddamn fortune.
有时我会想  我给家人的一切
You know, sometimes I think that everything I've given my family,
或许是不自觉
I've done maybe without knowing,
或许是为了让他们屈居我之下
or maybe to keep them beneath me.
我确实应该...
I certainly should have...
或许...鼓励沃尔特写自己的书
I don't know, encouraged Walt to write his own stories,
而不只是代管我的书
not just be a caretaker of mine.
就像你说的那样
Like you said I should.
当好琼妮的父亲而不只是给钱
And then be a father and not just a provider for Joni,
这也是你说的
like you also said.
我本可以对琳达和兰森更好
And I could have been kinder to Linda and Ransom...
老天  兰森
Jesus! Ransom.
那孩子跟我太像了
There's so much of me in that kid.
自信  愚蠢
Confident. Stupid.
还被保护得很好
I don't know, protected.
视人生如游戏  不计后果
Playing life like a game, without consequence.
直到甚至不能区分
Until you can't tell the difference
道具刀
between a stage prop
和真刀
and a real knife.
要知道  我不惧怕死亡
You know, I don't fear death.
但是  老天
But, oh, God,
我想在死前解决好一些事
I'd like to fix some of this before I go.
完美落幕
Close the book with a flourish.
我们就等着看吧
I guess we'll see.
是的
I guess we will.
你今天很累了
You had a long day.
想用点药吗
You wanna do drugs?
你是说好东西吗
You mean the good stuff?
要吗
Yeah?
快来  送我去极乐之境
Come on, send me to la-la land.
就一点  好吗
Just a tiny bit, okay?
为什么我人到中年才开始用吗啡
Why did I wait till my mid-age to become a morphine user?
真是个笨蛋
What a schmuck.
真是讨厌  这...
What a nudnik. This...
这东西是最棒的
This stuff is the best.
吗啡
痛力克
天啊
Oh, my God.
有什么问题吗
Is there a problem?
我刚刚给你注射了一百毫克这个
This is what I just gave you 100 milligrams of.
我搞混了
I messed up.
你给我注射了一百毫克好东西
You gave me 100 milligrams of the good stuff?
那个  好东西的用量应该是多少来着
Excuse me, what is the good stuff's dosage supposed to be?
别叫它好东西了  行吗
Let's not call it that right now, okay?
三毫克
Three milligrams.
那可少多了
Oh, that's much less.
那么接下来会怎样
So what happens?
我会给你紧急注射一针纳洛酮
I'm gonna give you an emergency shot of Naloxone,
否则你会在十分钟内死去
so you don't die in 10 minutes.
好吧  不用着急
Oh, well, no pressure.
你知道吗  这是个有趣
You know, this is an interesting
而且有效的杀人方法
and efficient method of murder.
我得把它记下来
I need to write this down.
所以  如果有人故意把药调包了
So, if someone switched the meds on purpose,
我就会在十分钟内死掉
I'd be dead in 10 minutes.
救不过来的那种死掉吗
Like stone-cold dead?
是的  你在五分钟内就会出现症状
Yes. You'll feel symptoms in five.
出汗  方向感迷失  然后...
Sweats, disorientation, and then...
对  那么大剂量  十分钟内  你的...
Yes. That big dose injected, within 10, your...
你的大脑...
Your brain...
是的  十分钟
Yes, 10 minutes.
从注射开始算
From the moment of injection?
现在还剩八分多钟了
It's eight-ish now.
即使受害者在刚出现症状时
And even if the victim called for an ambulance
就叫了救护车
when he first felt the symptoms
如果他住在像我们这样的乡下别墅
and if he lived in a great big country house like we do,
救护车至少得十五分钟才能到
the ambulance would take at least 15 minutes to arrive
那就为时已晚了
and it'd be too late.
如果受害者没有那个纳什么的药的话
If the victim didn't have the emergency Naxostuff.
玛塔
Marta?
-你有那个药吗  -有  我会找到它的
- Do you have the Naxostuff? - Yes, I'm gonna find it.
肯定有  因为它是医疗包自带的
I have it because it comes with the kit,
所以它应该在这里  肯定在
so it should be here. It has to be.
它就像...
It's like...
它不在这里  哈兰
It's not here, Harlan.
我不知道它为什么不在
I don't know why it's not here.
我得打电话了  好吗
So, I'm gonna use the phone, okay?
叫救护车
To call an ambulance.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
玛塔	  听我说
Marta, listen to me.
-哈兰  我得叫救护车  -停下
- Harlan, I need to call the ambulance. - Stop this!
-停下  玛塔  -得让他们过来
- Stop this, Marta! - They need to get here.
-没时间了  你必须听好  -什么
- There's no time! You have to listen! - What?
我要把全家人都叫过来
I'm calling the family!
你在做什么
What are you doing?
-你疯了吗  -别出声
- Are you nuts? - Don't make a noise.
-哈兰  我们得叫救护车  -玛塔  听我说
- Harlan, we have to call the ambulance. - Marta, listen to me!
我们没时间了
We don't have time!
-到底怎么回事  -听我说
- What's going on? - Listen to me!
如果你说的没错  我就死定了
Now, if what you said is true, I'm gone.
没有办法救我的
There's no saving me.
不  不
No, no.
我们只有六分钟
We have six minutes.
-不  我  -不  我们得让你摆脱嫌疑
- No, I... - Wait, no. We have got to get you out of this!
想想你妈妈
Think of your mom.
我妈妈
My mom?
玛塔  到我身后去  我身后
Marta, get behind me, get behind me.
别出声
Don't make a noise.
哈兰
Harlan?
玛塔
Marta?
一切都好吗
Everything all right?
-你好  琼妮  -我好像...你好
- Oh, hi, Joni. - I thought... Hi.
我好像听到了什么声音  一切都好吗
I thought I heard something. Is everything okay?
没事  我们很好  很好
No, no. We're fine. We're fine.
我只是刚把围棋棋盘打翻了  不好意思
Well, I just knocked over this Go board. Sorry about that.
-你们都没事  -是的  我们很好
- Everyone's all right? - Yeah, fine.
没事  回去睡吧  琼妮
No, no. Go to bed, Joni.
好吧
Okay.
也许明天我们可以谈谈家里...
Maybe we can talk tomorrow about the family...
明天  没问题
Tomorrow's fine.
-晚安  爱你  -爱你  再见
- Goodnight. Love you. 'Night. - Love you. Bye.
过来
Come on.
现在仔细听我说
Pay attention, now.
你的妈妈
Your mom
现在仍然是非法移民
is still undocumented.
如果这事最终归咎于你
And if this is your fault,
那她的身份就会被发现并被驱逐出境
she'll be found out and at best deported
你的家庭就会破碎
and your family will be broken.
我们不会让这发生的  对吗
We're not gonna let that happen, are we, huh?
但你必须严格按我说的做
But you have to do exactly what I tell you.
你愿意吗  玛塔
Will you do this, Marta?
为我最后做一件事
This last thing for me?
也为你的家人
For your family?
你想让我做什么
What do you want me to do?
下楼的时候动静越大越好
Go downstairs as noisily as you can
然后大声地说再见
and then say goodbye loudly.
沃尔特  我走了
Walt, I'm leaving.
尽量让他们留意时间
Call attention to the time...
天啊  已经午夜了
God, it's midnight already.
如果可以的话
If you can.
开车出大门
Drive out the gate.
为避开监控摄像头
Then to avoid the security cameras,
在大象雕塑之前停车
pull off the road before the carved elephant.
等等  是在雕塑之前还是之后
Wait. Was it before or after?
在大象雕塑之后
After the carved elephant.
不  他说的是之前  对吗
No, he said before. Was it?
在大象雕塑前后
Beafterfore the carved elephant.
该死
Oh, shit.
停好车  步行回房子
Park, and come back on foot up to the house.
从小门走侧院小路进来
Take the side yard pass through the little gate.
狗都认识你  它们应该不会叫
The dogs will know you, they shouldn't bark.
你得在不被人发现的情况下
You've got to get up to the third floor
回到三楼
without being seen.
唯一的方法就是从侧面的棚架爬上来
And the only way is to climb the side trellis
然后通过走廊上的暗窗进入房子
and come in through the trick hall window.
你在开玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding me.
我没开玩笑  就这样做
I am not. Do it.
而且千万不要弄出任何动静
And for God's sake, don't make any noise!
你进来之后  就是棘手的部分了
Once you're inside, now this is the tricky part...
这才是棘手的部分
This is the tricky part?
到我卧室里找到我的睡袍和帽子
Get my robe and cap from my bedroom
把它们穿戴上
and put them on.
哈兰...
Harlan...
这太疯狂了  我觉得我做不到
This is crazy. I don't think I can do that.
不  我们必须要做到无懈可击
No, we need to make this so airtight that the average cop
让普通警察完全忽略你的嫌疑
will entirely dismiss you as a suspect.
这听起来很疯狂  但会管用的
It sounds crazy, but it'll work.
沃尔特在外面抽烟  他会看到你出来
Walt is smoking outside, and he'll see you
隔着釉面窗户
through the glazed window.
爸爸  回去睡觉
Dad? Go back to bed.
有人看到你离开了
You were seen leaving.
监控摄像头也拍到你开车离开了
The security cameras show you driving off.
而二十分钟后
And 20 minutes later,
我儿子看到我活得好好的
I'm seen alive and well by my son.
你看  你从头号嫌疑人
You see, you've gone from suspect number one
变成了不可能的凶手
to an impossibility.
原路返回
Leave the way you came
不要被发现
and don't be seen.
兰森
Ransom?
你又回来了吗
Are you back again already?
开车回家
Drive home.
接下来的几天内
And sometime in the next few days
警察会来询问你
the police will question you.
不  不  不  不  不
No. No, no, no. No!
我不能说谎
I can't lie!
你知道我不能说谎  我会吐的
You know I can't lie! I'll puke!
那就不要说谎  只说部分的真相
Well, then don't lie. Tell fragments of the truth.
严格按这个顺序说
In this exact order.
我送他上楼
I took him upstairs.
我们像平常每晚一样下了围棋
We played our nightly game of Go.
中途他把棋盘打翻了
At some point, he knocked the board over
然后琼妮上楼来查看我们的状况
and Joni came up to check on us.
我给他注射了止痛药
I gave him pain medication.
他上周把肩膀拉伤了
He pulled his shoulder last week.
然后我就离开了  他一个人留在书房里
And I left him in his study.
午夜时分
At midnight
我对沃尔特说再见
I said goodbye to Walt,
然后就回家了
went home.
你给了他什么药
What kind of medication did you give him?
他受伤之后  我一直在给他
Since his injury, I've been giving him
注射一百毫克的痛力克
a 100 milligram IV push of Toradol.
那是一种非麻醉性止痛药
It's a non-narcotic analgesic.
为了帮助他入睡
And to help him sleep,
我还给了他三毫克的吗啡
three milligrams of morphine.
他的家人知道这些吗
And the family was aware of this?
是的  他们当然知道
Yes, of course.
你有注意到他
Did you notice anything strange
有任何不同寻常的行为吗
or off about his demeanor?
没有
No.
听起来没问题
Well, that sounds about right.
谢谢你  卡布瑞拉小姐
Thank you, Miss Cabrera.
我的宝贝
姐  大家快要过来
Hey, sis, people are gonna start getting here
参加纪念仪式了
for the memorial pretty soon.
你...
Are you...
你还好吗
Are you all right?
我只是在想爸爸的那些游戏
I was just thinking about Dad's games.
这一切就像是...
This all feels like one...
他笔下的情节  而非真实发生的事
Like something he'd write, not do.
我一直在等待揭示真相的时刻
I keep waiting for the big reveal.
到那时一切都说得通了
Where it'll make sense.
要是那样就好了
Wouldn't that be nice?
沃尔特
Oh, Walt.
我不觉得他是自杀的
I don't think he killed himself.
我不觉得  真不觉得
I don't. I really don't.
贺曼公司拍了一部电影
There's this Hallmark movie
叫《意外致死》  是丹妮卡·麦凯拉演的
called Deadly by Surprise with Danica McKellar.
她在里面演一个
And in it, she plays this wife
被丈夫下毒的妻子
who's getting poisoned by her husband,
但他是一点点下的毒
but he's doing it little by little,
所以她未曾察觉
so she doesn't know it
后来她发了疯  自杀了
and she goes crazy, and she kills herself.
我的表妹在法医办公室
And my cousin, who's a receptionist
当接待员
at the medical examiner's office,
她说这种事完全有可能发生
she says that stuff totally happens.
其疯狂程度还不及
It's not even 3% as crazy
她在那里见过的事情的百分之三
as the stuff she's seen come through there.
所以我只是...
So, I'm just like...
老天  没错
Oh, God, yeah!
别因为你爱他就喜欢他
I mean, don't like him because you love him.
不  我才不喜欢他  他就是个混蛋
No, I don't like him, he's an asshole.
但说不定我们就需要一个混蛋呢
But maybe an asshole is what we needed.
我的天  是啊
Oh, my God, yeah,
德国人在三十年代那会儿
an asshole is what Germany needed
-也需要一个混蛋  -又来了
- in 1930-whatever. - Here we go.
得了  琼妮  这两件事压根不能相提并论
Come on, Joni, those two things don't even conflate.
-问题在于...  -上帝啊
- There is the problem... - Oh, Jesus.
政治话题结束前我还是消失好了
I'm gonna disappear until the politics talk is done.
-你  我的朋友...  -要来点香槟吗
- You, my friend... - You want some champers?
不行  严格来讲我在工作
I can't. I'm technically working.
别维护特朗普了  理查德
Why don't you take off your red cap, Richard,
看看你周围
and look around you?
街上到处都是纳粹分子
The streets are literally flooded with Nazis.
不不不  不不不
No, no, no. No, no, no.
-我们正在失去我们的生活方式和文化  -正是
- We are losing our way of life and our culture. - That's right.
上百万的墨西哥人正在涌入
There are millions of Mexicans coming.
-天啊  你来真的吗  -这不是种族歧视
- Oh, God, really? - Don't make this a race thing.
你们总觉得这是种族歧视  如果是欧洲移民
You always make this a race thing. I would say the same thing
没错  这不是种族歧视
Yeah, this is not about race.
我也会说同样的话
if they were European immigrants.
是吗  如果是瑞士人
Oh, yeah? So, if the Swiss were, like,
-堵住了街道  -不不  我们接纳他们
- clogging in the streets... - No. No, no, we allow them in
然后他们就反客为主了
and they think they own what's ours.
他们把孩子们关在笼子里
They're putting children in cages!
-简直就是集中营  -没错
- I mean, these are camps! - Yes.
行了  琼妮
Come on, Joni,
没人觉得那是什么好事
nobody's saying that isn't bad,
但要怪就怪家长们
but the parents have some blame here.
因为什么  因为想给孩子创造更好的生活吗
Oh, for what? For wanting a better life for their kids?
-这不正是美国精神吗  -因为他们违法了
- Isn't that what America is... - For breaking the law!
-你不会想听这话的  -老天
- And you're gonna hate hearing this, - My God.
但这是实话  美国是属于美国人民的
but it's true, America is for Americans.
别指着我
Don't point at me.
玛塔去哪了  她还在这里吗
Where's Marta? Is she still here?
-老天  别这样  -玛塔
- Oh, God, don't. - Marta!
-过来  -别  理查德
- Come on over. - No, Richard.
过来  玛塔  请你过来
Come on over, Marta. Please, come over.
你开什么玩笑
You're shitting me.
玛塔
Marta,
你家里是乌拉圭的  但你用了正确的方式
your family is from Uruguay, but you did it right.
我是说  他们是通过合法途径移民的
I mean, what I'm saying is they did it legally.
她用了正确的方式
She did it the right way.
你努力工作
You work hard,
从零开始挣得财富
and you'll earn your share from the ground up.
就像爸爸  像我们所有人一样
Just like Dad and like all the rest of us.
我想你们都同意我说的话吧
And I'll bet you agree with me, right?
别烦这可怜的姑娘了  理查德
Oh, just leave the poor girl alone, Richard.
没事的  我只想听听她会怎么说
It's okay! I just wanna hear what she has to say!
没事的  玛塔  你尽管说
It's okay, Marta, you can speak.
亲爱的  你不一定要回答
Oh, sweetheart, don't feel pressure to answer.
-这只是...  -听着
- This is just a... - Look...
-请别这样  -如果你想成为美国人
- Please don't. - If you wanna become an American,
可以走合法途径
there are legal ways to do it.
但如果你违反了法律
But if you break the law,
那么就算你的初心再好
it doesn't matter how good your heart is,
也得承担后果
you gotta face the consequences!
你他妈的是疯了吗
Are you goddamn insane?
-我已经弄完了  -我警告你
- It's done. - I'm warning you.
于是我问她说
That's when I ask her, I'm like,
"托雅  说真的  人们都是怎么了"
"Tonya, what is wrong with people, literally?"
天啊  玛塔  怎么了
Oh, my God! Marta, what?
玛塔
Marta?
怎么了
What's the matter?
深呼吸
Whoa, whoa. Hey. Breathe.
-我的天  -玛塔  你还好吗
- Oh, my gosh. - Marta, are you okay?
弗兰  你还有藏货吗
Hey, Fran, do you still have your stash?
你需要可以随时来拿
Take 'em whenever you need 'em.
你给我那支电子烟后我就不怎么抽这些了
They're just drying out since you gave me that Juul.
谢了  弗兰
Thanks, Fran.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
抱歉  我真的非常抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm just very, very sorry.
-别再说抱歉了  老天  -我也不想这样
- Stop. Stop saying you're sorry. Jesus! - I hate this.
老天  我的心脏无法停止地...
Oh, God, my heart won't stop...
我无法...
I can't...
就是所有事情都...不用  谢谢你
It's just everything... No, thank you.
弗兰就把东西藏在这里吗
That's where Fran keeps her stash?
谁会去查看一个座钟呢
Who's gonna open a clock?
您想吃晚餐吗  奶奶
Do you want dinner, Nana?
晚餐  吃晚餐
Dinner? To eat?
-吃晚餐  -沃尔特
- To eat? - Walt?
-奶奶  -沃尔特  沃尔特  她好得很
- Nana? - Walt, Walt, she's fine.
她把三文鱼抹酱全吃光了
She ate the entire salmon spread already.
沃尔特  你告诉玛塔我们刚刚谈的事情了吗
Walt? Did you tell Marta yet, what we all talked about?
还没有  现在说合适吗
No, not yet. Is now a good time?
是的  现在正好  就现在
Yes. Yes, a very good time, right now.
好的
Oh, okay.
好了  冷静
All right. Calm down.
玛塔  我们好好谈了谈
Marta, we've been talking it over and, uh...
-你是不是吸大麻了  -没有
- Have you been smoking grass? - No.
快点
Come on.
玛塔  我们好好谈了谈
Marta, we've been talking it over,
我们全家
and, uh, the whole family,
我们愿意照顾你
we'd like to take care of you.
这话什么意思
What does that mean?
我们都认为你应该得到些什么
We all think that you deserve something.
我们愿意在经济上帮助你
Financially, we'd like to help you out.
你对爸爸一直很好
You were never anything but good to Dad
就凭这一点我们...
and because of that we...
你可以依靠我们
You can count on us.
好
Yeah.
我觉得你应该来参加葬礼的
I thought you should've been at the funeral,
但我少数不敌多数
by the way, I was outvoted.
侦探
Detective.
你还在这里
You're still here?
你认识哈兰吗
Did you know Harlan?
他认识我父亲
He knew my father,
我父亲多年前是一名警探
who was a police detective years ago.
他很敬重哈兰
My father respected Harlan.
说明哈兰一定很值得敬重
That says quite a lot.
这就是为什么你在这里吗
Is that why you're here?
现在在这里吗
Here now, here?
不是
No.
我在这里是想和你多聊上几句
I stayed hoping to speak to you a little more.
整件事背后另有隐情
Something is afoot with this whole affair.
我知道
I know it.
我想你也知道
I believe you know it, too.
所以你打算一直查下去吗
So you're gonna keep digging?
哈兰笔下的警探就会深查
Harlan's detectives, they dig.
他们会翻找  搜寻
They riffle and root.
就像寻找松露的猪一样
Truffle pigs.
我期待着《万有引力之虹》的终章
I anticipate the terminus of Gravity's Rainbow.
《万有引力之虹》
Gravity's Rainbow?
是本小说
It's a novel.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
-不过我还没看过  -我也没有
- I haven't read it though. - Neither have I.
没人看过
Nobody has.
不过我喜欢这标题
But I like the title.
它描绘了自然法则决定的事物轨迹
It describes the path of a projectile determined by natural law.
也就是  我的方法
Et voila, my method.
我观察客观事实
I observe the facts
不受大脑或心灵的主观偏见影响
without biases of the head or heart.
我找出轨迹的走向
I determine the arc's path,
闲庭信步至其尽头
stroll leisurely to its terminus
真相就出现在我眼前了
and the truth falls at my feet.
法医已经打算将这起案子判定为自杀
The medical examiner was ready to rule this a suicide,
但艾略特同意等48小时再做决定
but Elliott agreed to keep it pending for 48 hours.
明天一早
Tomorrow morning,
我就去房子及其周围搜查
I search the grounds and the house,
开始我的调查工作
begin my investigation.
我希望你能在边上辅助我
I want you to be by my side for it.
-什么  -做我的知己
- What? - My confidante.
我的耳目
My eyes and ears.
等一下  侦探  为什么是我
Wait, wait, Detective. Why me?
我相信你那颗善良的心
I trust your kind heart.
而且你是唯一一位
Also, you're the only one
从哈兰的死中得不到任何好处的人
who had nothing to gain from Harlan's death.
怎么样  华生
So how about it, Watson?
侦探先生
Hey, Detective?
以我对这一家人的了解
If you want my insight into the family...
他们都不可能是凶手
None of them are murderers.
这就是我的看法
That's my insight.
然而
And yet,
无论结果残忍还是令人欣慰
be it cruel or comforting,
真相终究会准确无误地被揭开
this machine unerringly arrives at the truth.
注定如此
That's what it does.
一向如此吗
Always?
明早八点
Tomorrow at 8:00.
我肯定漏掉了什么
I know I've missed something.
一定漏掉了什么
There's gonna be something I missed.
-哈兰  -但我知道你能行的
- Harlan. - But I know you can do this.
-我做不到  -你无需泯灭良知
- No, I can't. - Without losing your soul,
你只是不得不这么做  才能...
you have to do what you have to do to...
-不  -战胜这一切  赢得胜利
- No. - beat this and win.
哈兰  我做不到
Harlan, I can't.
-你能  而且必须做到  -不行
- You can. And you have to. - No.
为了我
For me.
快去
Right now!
哈兰  我得去求助
Harlan, I have to get you help.
只要照我说的做
You do as I say
一切都会没事的
and everything will be just fine.
不  不要
No. No.
我保证
I promise.
但...
But...
五十年前我就在这庄园工作了
Fifty years ago, I worked this estate.
要知道那时候的安保工作可不容易
You know, security back then was such that
你得带着枪去巡查
you had to make the rounds with a 94
要时刻保持警惕
and keep your ears open.
但如今我们拥有这么多现代科技
Now you've got all this modern technology.
监控录像在这里
Now, that's the video there.
我把案发当晚的录像保存了下来
I saved the tape from that night.
通常我会把录像带做消磁处理
Normally, I erase 'em with a magnetic degausser,
但这晚的我想还是保存下来得好  对吧
but in this case, I thought I'd just save it, you know?
以防万一
For security.
这边是实时画面
Now, uh, that's a live feed there.
为避开监控摄像头
To avoid the security cameras,
在大象雕塑之后停车
pull off the road after the carved elephant.
好的  能让我们看一下案发当晚的录像吗
All right, well, can we see the actual tape?
当然可以
Well, of course you can.
我全都录下来了
I recorded it SSLP.
这盘录像带有八个小时的内容
There's eight hours in that tape.
晚九点到早五点
9 p.m. to 5 a.m.
播放
像日本恐怖片一样
Looks like a Japanese horror movie.
能快进吗
You think we could scan forward on that?
是不是看过后七天就会死亡
Are we all gonna die in seven days?
怎么快进
How can we scan forward?
按住播放键
Oh, yeah, just hold the play button down
再按快进键  听到转动声就行了
and press FF until you hear it grind.
好了  应该快到
All right. Should be coming up now
派对结束的时间段了
to the time when the party ended.
怎么回事
What happened?
你得一直按着  不然带子就会弹出来
You gotta keep holding it down or else it'll eject.
监控录像
这机器年久失修了
That thing eats tapes like popcorn.
你的人能把这录像导入电脑
You think your guys can digitize this
让我们仔细看一下吗
so we could scan it properly?
应该没问题
Yeah, I think we can do that.
我拿着
I got it.
知道吗  这树林里的各种雕像
You know, all these statues that you see around here?
儿童奇幻系列丛书
都是按照《动物园悲剧》三部曲
They're all straight out of the series,
里面的形象制作的
The Menagerie Tragedy Trilogy.
-真酷  -棒极了
- Pretty cool. - Awesome.
是啊
Yeah.
贝尼  这地方是挺漂亮的
Benny, it's beautiful out here,
但你真的认为有人闯进房子
but do you really think someone broke into the house
谋杀了哈兰吗
and murdered Harlan?
我们是为了这个来的吗
Is that why we're out here?
我认为可能性不大
Oh, it is unlikely,
但如果真是这样  一定会留下踪迹
but if they did, there will be traces.
-我来拿着吧  -好
- Uh, I can hang on to that. - Yeah.
瓦格纳  你联系上...
Hey, Wagner, you got any luck on...
-那个谁没有  -兰森吗
- Uh, what's-his-name? - Ransom?
-对  -没有
- Yeah. - No.
只查到了地址
Did get an address though.
-是吗  -肯诺克街10号
-Yeah? - 10 Kenoak Street.
肯...肯诺克
Ken... Kenoak?
肯诺克
Kenoak.
读起来还挺带感的  是吧
It's a pleasant thing to say, isn't it?
肯诺克
Kenoak.
我在肯诺克街醒来
I awoke amid Kenoak.
这么多落叶和泥巴
All these leaves and mud,
我这双鞋算是没法要了
they're really gonna do a number on my boots, man.
泥巴  上周下过雨吗
Mud. Did it rain the past week?
-站住别动  -怎么了
- No, stay there! - What?
别动
Okay.
这里有脚印  所以...
We got footprints here, so, uh...
我要...
I wanna, um...
玛塔
Marta...
-别走了  -什么
- Stop. - What?
什么
What?
玛塔  在那别动
Marta, stay there.
-什么  -别  玛塔  别动  玛塔
- What? - No, Marta! Stay there, Marta.
-别过来  -我听不清  再说...
- No! No! - I couldn't hear. If you...
-你喊我了吗  -好吧
- Did you call me? - All right.
-算了  -借过
- All right. - Excuse me.
-没事  -过来
- All right. - Come here.
瓦格纳  我们得联系下局里
Wagner, we're gonna need to call the boys,
让他们派人过来
have 'em come down here,
检查一下这些脚印
take a look at all these tracks.
把脚印复制下来  往那边走
Get it taped off. Stay on that side.
-真抱歉  -小心  小心
- I'm sorry. - Watch out. Watch out.
好的
Okay.
希希  希希
Hussie? Hussie, hey.
狗能看透人的品性
Best judge of character is a dog.
-好孩子  -此话不假
- Good boy. - I've found that to be true.
小狗狗
My puppies!
他们计划在十点左右宣读遗嘱
They've got plans to read the will at around 10:00,
很快全家人就会到齐了
so, the whole family will be here soon.
我从没参加过遗嘱宣读
I've never been to a will reading.
也许
Oh, well...
你以为会像游戏节目一样精彩
You think it'd be like a game show,
但其实就像社区剧团演的报税会议一样无聊
but think of a community theater production of a tax return.
有什么是我们需要留意的
So, what are we looking for?
就是
Oh, you know,
所有可疑的或者不寻常的事情
anything suspicious or out of the ordinary.
你见到就会明白
You'll know it when you see it.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
吓我一跳
Sweet beans!
那...
Well...
早上好  斯隆贝夫人
Good morning, Mrs. Thrombey.
你准备好回到书房了吗
You think you could handle the study?
你的医疗包在哪
Where's your medical bag?
不知道  我放在这儿了
I don't know. I left it here.
每天晚上我都放在哈兰这儿
I always leave it here with Harlan at night.
一定是被作为证物拿走了
They must have taken it in as evidence.
我问一下
I'll look into that.
该死
Shit.
围棋棋盘是怎么被打翻的
How'd the Go board get knocked over?
玩闹的时候不小心碰掉的
We were just goofing around.
你在想什么
What are you thinking?
别闹 别闹
No! No, no, no!
让我猜猜
Oh, let me guess.
别闹了  停下
Hey! Stop. Stop.
停下  停下
Stop. Stop.
休·德莱斯戴尔
Hugh Drysdale?
兰森  叫我兰森  我的中间名
Ransom. Call me Ransom, it's my middle name.
只有佣人才叫我休
Only the help calls me Hugh.
好吧
Okay.
这位是瓦格纳警员
Uh, this is Trooper Wagner.
我是艾略特警督
I'm Lieutenant Elliott.
我们得问你几个问题
We just wanna ask a few questions.
等一下
Excuse me?
先生
Sir?
我们是执法人员
We're officers of the law!
你们要因为我不配合逮捕我吗
You gonna run me in? I don't feel like talking.
正烦着呢
I'm distraught.
贝尼  你要询问这家伙吗
Hey, Benny, you wanna ask this guy some questions?
这是要干什么  有什么安排吗
All right, what is this? What's this arrangement?
德莱斯戴尔先生
Mr. Drysdale.
在拍《犯罪现场调查之南方乡巴佬篇》吗
CSI: KFC?
弗兰妮
Hey, Frannie,
麻烦你倒一杯冰牛奶
how about a glass of cold milk?
混蛋
Hey, asshole.
她不叫那个名字  也不干那种活
Not her name, not her job.
梅格  你的激进社会正义学位读得怎么样了
Hey, Meg. How's the SJW degree coming?
-靠信托基金过活的废物  -够了  各位
- Trust fund prick. - All right, guys.
大家好
Hey. Everyone...
我要去另一个房间做准备工作
I'm just gonna be in the other room, setting up.
十分钟后开始宣读
Be ready in 10 minutes.
挺有意思  兰森  你缺席了葬礼
Funny, Ransom, you skipped the funeral,
却早早地到了遗嘱宣读会
but you're early for the will reading.
别这样  大家悼念的方式不尽相同
Okay, people grieve in different ways.
我们就不要...
Let's not...
可笑的是  你居然还好意思过来
You know what? It's funny you're here at all.
你费什么劲呢
Why are you even bothering?
我不禁这样问自己
That's what I'm asking myself.
这话是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
他知道我什么意思
He knows what it's supposed to mean.
等等  沃尔特  什么
Wait... Walt, what?
派对当晚雅各布就待在那个洗手间里
Jacob was in that bathroom the night of the party.
原来你整晚就待在那呢
Oh, that's where you were all night?
你整晚待在洗手间干什么
What the hell were you doing in the bathroom all night?
-什么也没干  -口诛笔伐叙利亚难民吗
- Nothing. - Swatting Syrian refugees?
不  我没有
No, I was not.
另类右派键盘侠
Alt-right troll.
玻璃心自由派
Liberal snowflake.
我都不知道你们说的是什么意思
I don't know what any of that means.
意思是你儿子有点变态
It means your son's a little creep.
是吗  我儿子变态吗
Oh! My son's a creep?
各位  回到正题...
Guys, just...
沃尔特  他当时在洗手间里
Walt, he was in the bathroom.
对  他在洗手间里
Yeah, he was in the bathroom.
对着死鹿的照片毫无快感地自慰
Joylessly masturbating to pictures of dead deer.
你来劲了是吧  理查德
You know what, Richard?
你想干一架吗
You wanna go?
来啊  死瘸子  干一架
You bet, skippy, let's go.
你想干一架是吧  来啊
You wanna go? Come on!
你最好小心点  伙计
You better watch out, man.
-沃尔特  马上住手  -狗娘养的
- Walt, stop it right now! - Son of a bitch!
-住手  停下来  -住手
- Stop it! Just stop! - Stop it!
放手  放开  理查德
Let go! Let go, Richard!
我等这一天等了很久了
I have been waiting for this my whole life!
-马上住手  -唐娜  我能控制住自己
- Stop it, right now! - Donna, I can handle myself!
-住手  -我能控制住
- Stop it! - I can handle it.
天啊
Oh, my God.
我们得多像这样聚聚
We gotta do this more often.
雅各布
Jacob.
我们知道你们想干嘛
We know where this is going.
你在哈兰办公室旁边的洗手间里
You were in the bathroom next to Harlan's office,
那天晚上他和兰森在里面起了争执
where he had the fight with Ransom.
你肯定听到了些什么
Now, you heard something.
说吧
Spill it.
我只听到了两句话
I just heard two things.
我的遗嘱
...my will.
"我的遗嘱"
"My will."
然后又大嚷大叫了一番
And then there was more yelling.
然后我就听到兰森说
And then I heard Ransom say...
"我警告你"
"I'm warning you."
兰森
Ransom...
那句话是什么意思
What's that mean?
我觉得那意味着我们的父亲终于醒悟过来
I think it means our father finally came to his senses
打算把这个混账玩意儿从他的遗嘱里划掉
and cut this worthless little brat out of his will.
看来你得卖掉宝马车
So I guess you're gonna have to sell the Beemer
退出乡村俱乐部
and give your notice at the country club,
戒掉那些高级毒品了
and kick whatever fashion drug you're on.
因为要是你觉得
Because if you think
在你跟家里人的关系闹成这么僵之后
that after all the bridges you've burned,
在你说过那些混账话之后
after all the shit you said,
就凭你在过去十年间对这个家的
after everything that you put this family through
所作所为
for the last 10 years,
你别以为我们中的任何一人还会支持你
that any of us are gonna support you
或者给你分一杯羹
that any of us are gonna give you,
就像老爸常说的
like Dad liked to say,
就算是"一毛钱"
"A single red dime..."
绝不可能
you're nuts!
儿子
Son...
父亲
Father.
哈兰告诉过你他要把你从遗嘱中除名吗
Did Harlan tell you he was gonna cut you out of the will?
没错
Yep.
那他可算是做了我们都没有勇气做到的事情
Well, then he's done what none of us were strong enough to do.
也许这件事终于能让你长大了
Maybe this might finally make you grow up.
这可能是发生在你身上最好的事情
This might be the best thing... that could ever happen to you.
谢谢  这就是我的母亲  女士们先生们
Thank you. My mother, ladies and gentlemen.
听着  这对你来说肯定不容易
Look, this is not gonna be easy for you,
但这是件好事
but it'll be good.
良药苦口利于病
Nothing good is ever easy.
放你妈的屁  琼妮
Up your ass, Joni.
你吸我们家的血都吸了多久了
You've had your teeth in this family's tit for a long time.
"放你妈的屁"  真是多谢夸奖
"Up your ass"? Oh, very nice.
-我直说了  吃屎去吧  -天啊  兰森
- Matter of fact, eat shit. - Oh, my God, Ransom.
-你说什么  -怎么样
- What? - How's that?
-再直白点  -请别在我儿子面前说那种话
- In fact... - Please do not use that word in front of my son.
-你吃屎  你也吃屎  -要不是我在练...
- eat shit. Eat shit. - If I wasn't practicing...
-吃屎  -你这个混蛋
- Eat shit. - You entitled prick!
我真想一巴掌扇翻你那该死的脸
I would slap that smug smile right off...
-你必须得吃屎去  -扇掉那得意的奸笑
- Definitely eat shit. - ...of your goddamn face!
你也吃屎  你们都吃屎去吧
Eat shit. You can all eat shit.
我一点屎都不会吃
I'm not eating one iota of shit!
是谁说遗嘱宣读会很无聊来着
What was that about will readings being boring?
看来这次是例外了
The exception that proves the rule.
混蛋
Asshole.
"我警告你"
"I'm warning you."
兰森说  "我警告你"
Ransom said, "I'm warning you."
你刚刚也听到兰森说的了
Well, you heard Ransom in there.
他这种人就是会说那种话
That's the kind of thing he says.
你想要吗  你想要吗
You want this? You want this?
这是什么
What do we have here?
这断面看起来还很新
This looks like a relatively fresh break.
没错  就在那
Yep. Right there.
等等
Wait a minute.
这没道理啊
Well, that doesn't make sense.
那扇窗户通向哪里
Where's that window?
再吃点饼干怎么样  休
How about some more cookies, Hugh?
-你想再吃点饼干吗  -真好  太好了
- You want some more cookies? - That's great. That's great.
说不定哈兰在遗嘱里给你留了一杯冰牛奶
Hey, maybe Harlan left you a cold glass of milk in his will.
混蛋
Asshole.
指给我看  但不要踩地毯
Show me. But stay off the carpet.
是暗窗
It's the trick window
是《四季谋杀》里的
from A Kill For All Seasons.
警员  你可以拿一下这个吗
Trooper, here, will you? Take this.
干燥的泥土痕迹
Traces of dried mud.
我怀疑整条走廊上都有这样的痕迹
I suspect they go the length of the hallway.
有脚印吗
Footprints?
没有  只有泥屑
No, just traces.
根据这地毯最后一次清洗的时间推断
Yeah, depending on when this thing was last cleaned,
这痕迹指不定是什么时候留下来的  对吧
this could have happened at any time, right?
不对  这里也有类似的痕迹
No, that would not explain this.
分析那上面的泥
Analyze that mud.
肯定会跟这些泥痕相符
It will match these traces.
把这个带去给杰米
Take this to Jamie.
屋外肯定有类似的泥痕
And you will find similar samples
沿着棚架一路分布到窗台
leading up the trellis on the outside of the house.
在派对当晚
On the night of the party,
一个不想被发现的人爬上了棚架
somebody who did not want to be heard climbing those steps,
费了九牛二虎之力
went to a great deal of trouble
闯进了哈兰·斯隆贝的房间
to break into Harlan Thrombey's rooms.
游戏开始了  对吧  华生
The game is afoot, eh, Watson?
感谢大家能像这样聚在一起
Well, thank you all for getting together like this.
法律上没有如此必要
It isn't legally necessary,
但我想因为你们都在城里
but I thought because you're all in town,
而且你们中的一些人很快就要离开
and some of you are leaving soon...
打扰一下
Excuse me.
抱歉
Uh, I'm sorry.
女士们先生们  我想礼貌地请你们
Ladies and gentlemen, I would like to gently request
在案件调查结束前都留在城里
that you all stay in town until the investigation is completed.
他是在礼貌地请你们
Yeah, well, he's gently requesting,
但我得命令你们待在城里
but I'm gonna have to make that an order.
在我们调查清楚之前谁也不许走
No one move until we figure this all out.
什么
What?
我们能问为什么吗
Can we ask why?
-案情有什么变化吗  -没有
- Has something changed? - No.
是没有变化  还是我们不能问
No, it hasn't changed? Or no, we can't ask?
斯蒂文斯先生...
Mr. Stevens...
你可以继续了
You may continue.
好  那么...
Right. Well...
我认为大家应该齐聚一堂的另一个原因是
The other reason I thought this gathering would be, uh, beneficial
哈兰在死前一周更改了他的遗嘱
is because Harlan altered his will a week before he died.
他把遗嘱密封了
He sealed it.
他让我等到他死后
He asked me not to submit it to the courts
再将遗嘱提交给法院认证
for probate until after his death.
所以  如果谁对哪里有疑虑
So, if anyone is confused about anything,
我们都聚在一起  可以当场讨论
we're all together, we can talk.
尽管我并不认为
Although I don't imagine any of it
遗嘱会有多么复杂的地方
is going to be that complicated.
哈兰的资产包括...
Uh, Harlan's assets included...
-这栋房子  -这栋房子
- The house. - The house,
这完全归他所有
which he owned outright.
六千万美金
$60 million.
对  各种形式的总计六千万美金
Yes. $60 million in various cash accounts
包括现金账户与投资
and investments.
当然了  还有
And of course,
真正的财产所在
the real asset,
烈酒如血出版公司的全部所有权
sole ownership of Blood Like Wine,
也就是他的出版公司
his publishing company.
他变更遗嘱时还写了一份声明
He also wrote up a statement when he was making the changes
他希望能先读这个
and he wanted that read first.
"亲爱的琳达  沃尔特和琼妮
"Dearest Linda, Walter, and Joni...
我做出的选择可能会让你们某些人吃惊
Some of you may be surprised by the choice I've made here.
除名的过程并不好受
No pleasure was taken in the exclusion.
并且这份遗嘱的目的
And its purpose was not to sow
不是为了在这个家里埋下更深的分歧
greater discord in the family,
恰恰相反
Quite the opposite.
请从容地接受它  不要心怀怨怼
Please accept it with grace and without bitterness,
但请你们接受它
But do accept it,
这是最好的选择  爸爸"
It's for the best. Dad."
好的  完全不复杂
Well, yeah, not too complex at all.
读起来很快
This will be quick.
"我  哈兰·斯隆贝  头脑清醒身体健康"
"I, Harlan Thrombey, being of sound mind and body"
然后是一堆废话
and yada-yada-yada...
"我特此将我的所有资产
"I hereby direct that all my assets,
包括流动资产与固定资产
both liquid and otherwise...
尽数留给玛塔·卡布瑞拉
I leave in their entirety to Marta Cabrera.
我持有的烈酒如血出版公司全部所有权
My entire ownership of Blood Like Wine publishing,
尽数留给玛塔·卡布瑞拉
I leave in its entirety to Marta Cabrera,
公司的书目版权
The copyright of its catalogue likewise
我也同样尽数留给玛塔·卡布瑞拉"
I leave in its entirety to Marta Cabrera."
什么
What?
-什么  -不
- What? - No.
-这不...这不...  -不
- That's not... That's... No. - No.
-这不可能  -不
- That can't be. - No.
能让我看一看吗  艾伦
Can I see that please, Alan?
-可以  没问题  -谢谢
- Yeah. It's right. - Please.
这不可能合法
This can't be legal.
它没问题
It's right.
-你知道  他...  -老天
- You know, he was... - Oh, my God.
就没有保护条例...
Aren't there safeguards...
艾伦  肯定出错了
Alan, there's a mistake.
我不知道该说什么
I don't know what to say.
我们是他的家人  所以...
We're his family, so...
这不可能
It's not possible.
就没有防范这种情况的保护条例吗
Are there safeguards against this?
思维清晰  某些...
Right mind. Something...
-你知道  -艾伦  听我说...
- You know... - Alan, listen...
-他在用药  -他死前的日子里
- He was on medication. - In his final days,
他在使用大量药物
he was on a great deal of medication.
吗啡吗  对  吗啡
Morphine? All right, morphine.
-我不知道  -这真让人不解
- I mean, I don't know. - This is confusing.
-她看似是家人  -艾伦  你可以...
- She seems like family... - Alan, you can take...
-但并不是真正的家人  -拿起这张纸
- but she's not our family. - this piece of paper
擦擦你的屁股  然后滚出去了
and shove it right up your ass, and get out!
还有你们这些警察  也滚出去
And, you cops, too, out.
-琳达  -出去  马上
- Linda? - Out! Right now.
-琳达  -不  理查德  我们得谈谈
- Hey, Linda? - No, Richard, we need to talk.
这件事我们要抗争到底  我们哪里也不去
We need to fight this thing. We're not going anywhere.
我说了滚出去
I said get out!
我们是斯隆贝家族  见鬼
We are the Thrombeys, God damn it!
这还是我们的房子
This is still our house!
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
"同样地  在鹿生路2号的房子
"Likewise the house at 2 Deerborn Drive
以及里面的所有财物
And all belongings therein,
我也留给玛塔·卡布瑞拉"
I leave to Marta Cabrera."
你这个小贱人
Oh, you little bitch!
-你这个小贱人  -琳达
- You little bitch! - Linda?
你早就知道这事吗
Did you know about this?
你早就开始谋划这事了是吗
Were you in on this from the beginning?
-这简直难以置信  -冷静
- This is unbelievable! - Easy.
不不不  我只想知道  你做...
No, no, no! I just wanna know. What were you...
你做了什么  你是不是在跟我父亲上床
What were you doing? Were you boinking my father?
-"上床"  -不  不  不
- "Boinking"? - No, no, no.
大家都应该冷静一点
I think everybody just needs to cool their jets.
你和爷爷上床了  你这肮脏的非法移民后代
You had sex with my grandpa, you dirty anchor baby!
控制住你们的情绪
Now hold your horses.
同时  我建议你该跑了
And in the meantime, I'd maybe run.
等等  等等  等等  玛塔
Wait, wait, wait, Marta?
好了  请你们...
Now, would you please...
-各位  请留步  -玛塔  回答我们
- Ladies and gentlemen, please. - Marta, talk to us.
玛塔
Marta?
等一等
Wait a minute.
我完全理解你现在的感受
I totally understand how you must be feeling right now.
-你不能走  -你可以对我说
- You cannot leave! - You can talk to me.
我不知道说什么  我不知道
I don't know what to say. I don't know.
-冷静  冷静  -玛塔  请你...
- Calm down. Calm down. - Marta, please...
玛塔  听着  亲爱的...
Marta, listen, darling...
我不知道怎么回事  我不知道他为什么...
I don't know what's happening. I don't know why he...
各位  我也很困惑  我需要思考
Guys, I'm also confused. I need to think!
玛塔  你在听吗
Marta! Are you listening?
我插不上话
I can't catch up!
-我懂  我懂  -理查德  开门
- I understand. I understand. - Richard! Open the door!
打开车门
Open up that door!
-你们吓着她了  -我打不开门
- You are scaring her! - I can't open the damn door!
玛塔  走  玛塔  走
Marta, go. Marta, go.
玛塔  你得理解
Marta, you have to understand.
他是我们的父亲
He is our father!
-玛塔  听我说  -玛塔  别听他们的
- Marta, listen to me. - Marta, don't listen to them.
我在这里
I'm here.
我不用推特了
I'm not on Twitter anymore.
在照片墙上私信我  好吗
So dm me on Instagram, okay?
我想跟你谈谈
I wanna talk to you.
兰森
Ransom!
到底是怎么回事
What the hell's going on?
我认为这可能是
I think this could be the best thing
发生在你们身上最好的事情
to happen to all of you!
他那是什么意思
What does he mean by that?
理查德  你怎么没拦住她
Richard, why didn't you stop her?
我要怎么做
What am I supposed to do?
用牙咬住保险杠吗
Grab the bumper with my teeth?
好了  不过说实在的  这是怎么回事
Okay, seriously, though, what the hell?
再给我一个空碗
Hey. I'll take an extra bowl.
没问题
Sure.
你看起来像是要晕过去了
You look like you're gonna pass out.
你今天吃过东西吗
Have you eaten anything today?
吃点
Eat.
这就是个噩梦
This is a nightmare.
所以为什么
So why?
-为什么  -为什么
- Why? - Why?
这可是全部财产
Hey. This is everything.
肯定有个更重要的原因  你知道那个原因
There's gotta be a bigger reason why, and you know it.
作出这个决定主要是因为你们
Well, how about it had to do more
而非因为我  这个理由如何
with you guys than with me?
对
Yeah.
对  这是唯一合理的解释
Yeah, it's the only thing that makes sense.
他跟你说过什么吗
Did he tell you anything?
只说了我一分钱都分不到
Only that I wasn't getting a cent.
那是因为他希望
That's because he wanted you
你能像你妈妈一样白手起家
to build something from the ground up
-白手起家  -"白手起家"
- like your mom. - "To build something from the ground up."
对  我妈妈是白手起家创业的
Yeah, my mother built her business from the ground up
用的是我外公给的一百万美金借款
with a million-dollar loan from my grandfather.
我父亲没有任何股份  她让他签了婚前协议
My father owns none of it. She made him sign a prenup.
他生活在恐慌中
He lives in fear.
我知道我外公希望通过这样做
And I know that's what my grandfather was trying
来防止我变成我爸那样
to protect me from by doing this
我也知道我不该说这话
and I know I shouldn't say this out loud,
但他告诉我的时候  我...
but when he told me, I...
老天
Jesus.
我差点杀了他
I could have killed him.
离开派对后   我开着车
After I left the party though, I was driving.
漫无目的  在夜色深处  我的思绪突然
Nowhere, just in the night, and I had this, um...
无比清明
Clarity.
我意识到从那一刻起
Like, from here on out,
我得自己照顾自己了
I was gonna have to fend for myself.
而那感觉...
And that felt...
很好
Good.
那个老混蛋
The old bastard.
玛塔  我知道三件事
Marta, I know three things.
第一
One...
我知道他不是自杀
I know he didn't commit suicide.
-你为什么这么想  -这不是我想的
- What makes you think that? - I don't think it.
我就是知道
I know it.
因为我了解我爷爷
Because I knew my granddad.
或许只有你和我才了解他
Maybe you and I were the only two who knew him,
所以你不能在这件事上糊弄我  因为第二
so you're not gonna bullshit me on this because, two...
我知道你撒谎时会吐
I know lying makes you puke.
去年独立日玩杀人游戏时知道的
'Cause of that mafia game last Fourth of July.
第三
And three...
我知道你刚吃下了
I know you just ate
一整盘的烤豆子和香肠
a full plate of baked beans and sausage.
所以
So...
看着我的眼睛
Look me in the eye
告诉我爷爷究竟是怎么回事
and tell me what happened to my grandfather.
-你这个混蛋  -玛塔
- You asshole. - Marta,
都告诉我
tell me everything.
艾伦  一定还有别的办法
Alan, there have got to be options here.
没有
No.
我不知道我还能重复多少遍
I don't know how many times
同样的两条信息
I can repeat the same two pieces of information.
如果哈兰改变遗嘱时神志清醒
If Harlan was of sound mind when he made the changes,
我们都确认了他是的...
and we all confirmed that he was...
神志清醒会这么做
Would a sound mind do this?
怎么会  怎么可能清醒
How... Sound, how?
这种行为正证明了他并不清醒
The very action speaks to unsoundness.
法律上来讲不是  不是的
Not legally. No.
你们不喜欢他所做的
You not liking what he did
并不能证明他没有遗嘱能力
does not speak to testamentary capacity.
那不当影响呢
What about undue influence?
对  不当影响  怎么讲
Yeah! Undue influence, how about that?
你是刚在网上搜到的吗
Did you just google that?
听着  如果玛塔设法操控了爸爸
Look, if Marta was manipulating Dad somehow
-如果我们发现  -如果她想办法
- and if we found out... - If somehow, she had gotten...
-她想办法...  -她控制了他...
- that somehow she was... - her hooks into him...
你们需要有确切的证据
You need a strong case for that.
"法官大人  她通过努力工作与幽默
"Your Honor, she endeared herself to him
得到了他的喜爱"
"through hard work and good humor."
那没有任何用处
That won't cut the salami.
那凶手规则呢
What about the slayer rule?
是我刚在网上搜到的
I did just google that.
凶手规则显然不适用于此案
The slayer rule obviously doesn't apply here.
凶手规则是什么东西
Well, what the hell is the slayer rule?
就是说如果继承人被判决为
Well, it's if someone is convicted
杀害被继承人的凶手
of killing the person,
那就不能继承其遗产
they don't get their inheritance.
无需法院判决
Not even convicted.
哪怕继承人在民事法庭上被认定为
Even if they're held responsible
对被继承人的死负有责任都不行
for their death in civil court.
像O·J·辛普森那样
Like O.J.?
对  像O·J·辛普森那样
Yes, like O.J.
但哈兰是自杀的
But Harlan committed suicide.
布莱克侦探
Detective Blanc?
你说调查还在进行
You said the investigation is ongoing.
你特别声明过
You made a point of that.
你怀疑是他杀吗
Do you suspect foul play?
麻烦叫我布兰克先生
Mr. Blanc, if you please...
还有很多都不明确
There is much that remains unclear,
但是的
but yes,
我怀疑是他杀
I suspect foul play.
玛塔
Marta?
我还没有排除任何一个人的嫌疑
I have eliminated no suspects.
你真是满嘴放炮
You're full of shit.
我不信任这个穿粗花呢西装的家伙
I don't trust this guy in the tweed suit.
艾伦  上帝保佑你  你真是没用
And, Alan, God bless you, you're useless.
谢谢
Thank you.
这件事只有一个办法
There's only one answer to this.
她得宣布放弃继承
She has to renounce the inheritance.
她知道应该这么做
She knows it's what she should do.
-她就应该这么...  -这才是正确的做法
- That's exactly what she... - It's the right thing to do.
-对吧  -没门...
- Right? - No way...
这才符合道德
It's the moral thing.
-妈妈  -她会这么做的
- Mom. - She'll do it.
如果爷爷想把一切给玛塔
If Granddad wanted to give Marta everything,
那就是他的意愿
then that's what he wanted.
不是
No.
他不是这样的  他爱我们
This wasn't him. He loved us.
他想要我们被照顾好
He wanted us taken care of.
他想让你接受高等教育
He wanted you to have an education.
梅格
Meg,
你觉得我能付得起你的学费吗
you think I can pay for your school?
我知道
I know.
我自己说出来都觉得离谱
Just saying it, it sounds insane,
但这都是真的
but it's all true.
我觉得布兰克从一开始就盯上了我
And I think Blanc's been on to me from the start.
我不在乎自己会不会进监狱  但我妈妈
I don't care if I go to jail, but my mom,
我妹妹
my sister?
我们...
We...
你要说点什么吗
You gonna say something?
我一直以为只有我
I always thought I was the only one
能在围棋上赢过他
that could beat him at Go.
我总认为那意义非凡
Always thought that meant something.
是  我知道你是的
Um, yeah, I know you did.
那晚在派对上
That night at the party,
我和他的最后一次谈话
my last conversation with him...
最后的争执  他就是这么跟我说你的
My last argument, that's what he told me about you.
他说你在围棋上比我赢过他更多次  我就想
That you beat him at Go more than I do, and I thought...
告诉我这种事也太奇怪了
What a strange thing to tell me.
我现在明白了
Think I get it now.
或许这一点确实意义非凡
Maybe it did mean something.
我不会告诉我的家人
I'm not gonna tell my family shit.
你不会进监狱
You're not gonna go to jail.
那个侦探不会抓住你
That detective is not gonna catch you.
你也不会放弃遗产
And you're not gonna give up the money.
这是爷爷想给你的
This is what Granddad wanted for you.
想想他为此都做了什么
I mean, think about what he did to go through with this.
他这是为了自己  为了家人
He wanted this for himself, he wanted this for the family.
也是为了你
And he wanted it for you.
你都走到这一步了
You've come this far.
让我来帮你继续吧
Let me help you go all the way.
怎么回事  你不是这样的人
What's going on? This isn't you.
你现在就可以告发我
You could just turn me in right now
而且还能拿到你的那份遗产
and still get your cut of the inheritance.
为什么
Why?
因为去他妈的家人
Because fuck my family.
我能帮你摆脱这些
I can help you get away with this.
然后
And then,
你要给我我的那份遗产
you're gonna give me my cut of the inheritance.
大团圆结局  大家都是赢家  你  我
Happy ending. Everybody wins. You, me...
哈兰
Harlan.
是啊
Yeah.
说定了
Deal?
来电
梅格
Meg.
玛塔
Marta...
刚刚大家都疯了
That was nuts.
我知道
I know.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
还好  你呢
Yeah. Are you?
是的  我还好  我...
Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine, I...
听我说  没人知道我打给你了  我...
Look, no one knows I'm calling you, I just...
我想...
I wanted to...
我为大家刚才的行为向你道歉
I wanted to say sorry for how everyone was.
还有...
And, uh...
我想问  你打算怎么做
I guess, I wanted to ask, what are you gonna do?
什么意思
What do you mean?
就是...
Well, the...
遗嘱  你打算怎么做
You know, with the will, what are you gonna do?
你觉得我该怎么做
What do you think I should do?
你应该做你觉得正确的事
You should do whatever you think is right.
是这样  我...
Look, I...
我觉得你应该还给我们
I think you should give it back to us.
爷爷总是照顾我们
Granddad always took care of us.
我们是他的家人
You know, we're his family.
我知道他对你来说也像是家人
And I know he was like family to you,
但我们才是他真正的家人
but we're his actual family.
是
Yeah.
还有...听着  玛塔
And... Look, Marta,
你知道这不公平
you know this isn't fair.
我们一直都对你很好
We've always been good to you
你就像家人一样  我们也会照顾你
and you're like family, and we'll take care of you,
但你要纠正这一切
but you have to make things right.
你知道怎样才是正确的
You know what's right.
玛塔
Marta...
妈妈没钱了
Mom's broke.
她说我得退学了
And she says I'm gonna have to drop out of school.
不  不  不  梅格
No. No, no, Meg.
听着  我不会让你退学的
Listen, I won't let that happen.
无论你需要多少钱  我都会给你
Whatever money you need, I'll give it to you.
我会支持你
I'm here for you.
我想让你知道我会照顾你的
And I want you to know I'm gonna take care of you,
我保证
I promise that.
好吗
Okay?
谢谢
Thanks.
一旦我...
And once I...
行吧
Okay then.
布兰克在房子里发现疑点了吗
Did Blanc find anything suspicious at the house?
有  他发现楼上有泥巴
Yes, he found mud upstairs.
是我从窗户爬进去的地方
Where I broke in through the window.
糟糕
Shit.
有清晰的脚印吗
Identifiable prints?
没有
No.
很好  好的
Good. Okay.
很好
Good.
你这几天低调点
You lay low for a couple days,
等待调查结束  调查一定会结束的
wait for this investigation to blow over, and it will.
因为不论布兰克这家伙自诩有多牛
'Cause no matter how good this Blanc guy thinks he is,
他终归没找到什么证据
he's got nothin'.
别紧张
Hey, relax.
玛塔  快起来
Marta, get your ass up!
到底发生什么事了
What the hell is happening?
来了个人  外面还有一大堆
There's a guy here, and a bunch of stuff.
一切都要疯了  我们变有钱了吗
Everything's going crazy. Are we rich?
可能吧  爱丽丝  我不知道
Maybe, Alice. I don't know.
我都不知道那是什么意思
I don't even know what that means,
28个未接电话
但你最好快起来  好吗
but you better get your ass up, okay?
我们不太了解玛塔·卡布瑞拉
We don't know much about Marta Cabrera,
畅销推理小说作家撇开家人
将遗产留给私人看护
-以及她和哈兰·斯隆贝...  -天啊
- or her exact relationship... - Oh, my God...
到底是什么关系
with Harlan Thrombey...
玛塔  这到底怎么回事
Marta, what is all this?
-只知她是他的家庭护士  -你做了什么
- beyond being his home nurse. - What did you do?
拍的就是这里吗
Is that here?
是的
Oh, yeah, it is.
等等  所以是真的吗
Wait, so is that true?
我们变有钱了
Are we rich?
这故事精彩得...
This is a story so compelling...
-我的天  -让人以为是他自己编出来的
- Oh, my God. - you would think he had written the story himself.
麦金塔  激光唱机
早上好  斯隆贝夫人
Good morning, Mrs. Thrombey.
为何天意总让年轻人承载悲痛
Why is grief the providence of youth?
我不知道
I don't know.
但我想年龄会加深所有的情感
But I'd imagine that age deepens all feelings.
包括悲痛
Including grief.
抱歉我过了这么久才过来
This was a long walk to offering condolences
对你痛失爱子表示哀悼
for the loss of your son.
我还想请问你  恕我冒昧
And asking you, if it isn't presumptuous of me,
不是故意要把你的家人想得太坏
not to think too harshly of your family,
我猜我是第一个安慰你的人吧
if I am, as I suspect, the first to console you.
他们还年轻  不是吗
They're young, aren't they?
我以为年岁的增长
One thing I assume of age
会导致厌倦
is weariness.
真希望我不会每天感到更加厌倦
Damned if I don't get more tired every day.
厌倦于我的工作
Tired of what I do.
沿着蛛丝马迹
Following arcs like lobbed rocks,
直至那不可避免的真相
the inevitability of truth.
但是问题的复杂性和灰色地带
But the complexity and the gray
不在于真相本身
lie not in the truth
而在于你找出真相后要怎么办
but what you do with the truth once you have it.
我想你有什么事想要跟我说吧
I think you have something you wanna tell me.
我觉得你观察入微
I think you're very perceptive
一定可以告诉我  你儿子派对那天晚上
and very capable of telling me what you saw
你看到了什么
the night of your son's party.
我很乐意等
But I'll happily wait.
我不着急
I'm in no rush.
事实上
In fact,
我发现跟你一块儿坐在这里
I find it quiet pleasant
非常愉悦
sitting here with you.
律师们来过了
Lawyers were here.
看起来像是非常出名的律师
Very big lawyers, it looked like.
他们留下来这堆东西  还有名片
They left all this stuff and business cards.
还有一大堆别的东西
And there was a pile of other stuff
我到家的时候发现的
when I got home.
我不喜欢这样  玛塔
I don't like any of this, Marta.
我也不喜欢
I don't like it either.
我从后门溜出去
I'm slipping out the back.
我晚点就回来  别跟任何人说话
I'll be back later. Please don't talk to anyone.
沃尔特
Walt?
是  我来
Yeah, I came, uh...
你怎么样了
Hey, how you doin'?
沃尔特  我想让你知道
Walt, I want you to know
我事先对此毫不知情
that I didn't know about any of this.
-我们知道你不知情  -这事...
- We know you didn't. - This is...
我们知道你不知情
We know you didn't.
是  我们昨天都有点失控了
Yeah, we all kind of went a little crazy yesterday.
-可以理解  -是的
- Understandable. - Yeah.
我都还没看过这些
I haven't even looked at all this, yet.
玛塔·卡布瑞拉收
肯定是本地律师和会计
It must just be local lawyers and accountants
他们看到新闻了  想要抢这单生意
who saw the news and wanna get a jump on it.
是啊  你应该小心点
Yeah. I'd be careful of all of it.
玛塔  你打算放弃遗产吗
Marta, is it your intention to renounce the inheritance?
这是哈兰的意愿
This is what Harlan wanted.
没错  但是
Yeah, but...
哈兰让你很为难  我是说
Harlan put you in a very hard position here. I mean,
他这样很不公平
it was unfair of him.
你知道
I mean, you see
这样做所导致的压力和对你隐私的窥探
the kind of press and scrutiny that this kicks up
我们知道  你母亲的事...
and we know, with your mother...
我母亲
My mother?
是的
Yeah.
梅格跟你说什么了
What did Meg tell you?
这跟那个没...
Oh, this isn't about...
你误会了
You're missing the point.
我们不会拿这件事来害你
We don't wanna attack you with this,
但是  玛塔  如果你母亲
but, Marta, if your mother
是非法进入美国的  那就是犯罪
came into the country illegally, criminally.
你若是继承了遗产
And you've come into this inheritance,
随之而来的所有调查
with all the scrutiny that entails,
我担心这件事会被曝光
I'd be afraid that could come to light.
我们不希望发生这种事
And that's what we wanna avoid here.
我们可以把这件事压下来
We can protect you
即使曝光了
from that happening,
我们也能保护你
or if it happens.
你是说即使这件事曝光了
So you're saying that even if it came to light,
以你们家的资源  你们也可以帮我解决
with your family's resources, you could help me fix it?
是的
Yeah.
是的  找到合适的律师就行
Yeah, with the right lawyers, you know?
这帮本地菜鸟不行
Not these local guys,
要找纽约的律师  华盛顿的律师
but New York lawyers, DC lawyers,
加上足够的资源  就可以解决
with enough resources put toward it, yes.
不是说一定会出现这种情况
Not that that ever even needs to come up,
但是没错  可以解决
but, yes.
好的  很好
Okay, good.
好的
Okay?
因为哈兰把你们所有的资源都给了我
Because Harlan gave me all your resources.
那就是说以我的资源
So that means with my resources,
我就可以解决这件事
I'll be able to fix it.
所以我想我能找到合适的律师
So I guess I will find the right lawyers.
玛塔  这...
Marta, that's...
你最好确定
You better be sure that's
这是你想要的
what you want.
我知道你做了什么
来电
疑似贝努瓦·布兰克
我知道你做了什么
姓名  玛塔·卡布瑞拉
我不知道  这是什么
I don't know... What's this?
是我医疗包上的标签
It's my medical bag tag.
这人不知怎么拿到了我的医疗包
They have my medical bag for some reason.
好吧  不过这是哈兰的血液毒理学报告
Okay, but this is a photocopy of just the header
首席法医办公室
马萨诸塞州诺福克郡
开头部分的复印件
of a blood toxicology report on Harlan.
病人姓名  哈兰·斯隆贝
玛塔  这样大家就知道吗啡过量的事了
Marta, this is gonna show the morphine overdose.
那我完蛋了
So I'm screwed?
你怎么懂这些
How do you know all this stuff?
有一个暑假我给哈兰当过研究助理
I was Harlan's research assistant for a summer.
我知道你做了什么
但这算哪门子敲诈
But what kind of blackmail scheme is this?
我的意思是  真正的证据
I mean, the actual evidence
远在犯罪实验室里
is sitting up the street, at the crime lab.
这上面没提要求  没说见面地点
There's no demands, there's no meeting place.
给你写这封信有什么目的
What's the point in sending you this?
首席法医
诺福克郡
诺福克郡法医办公室
可能需要半个小时
It could be a half hour.
或一个小时  得看情况
It could be an hour. It depends.
我们要确保...
We wanna make sure...
所以需要点时间
So, it could take a while.
-发生什么了  -我会通知你的
- What's the cheese? - But I'll let you know.
-谢谢你  队长  -好的  没问题
- Thank you, Chief. - Yeah. No problem.
凌晨五点
5:00 a.m.
所有安全系统都被触发了
Security systems here are all triggered.
火势发展迅速
Now, this thing went up really quick,
这意味着血样和记录
so that means blood stores, records,
之类的东西  都毁掉了
anything of that nature, it's all gone.
当时没有员工在场
There were no employees here,
谢天谢地
so, thank God for that.
监控摄像头呢
What about security cameras?
在那里
Oh, yeah.
说到监控
Speaking of security,
斯隆贝庄园的监控录像
the surveillance tape at the Thrombey estate
不知为何被干扰损坏了
was all scrambled for some reason.
好吧
Yeah.
尸检还有什么结果没出吗
What's still pending from the autopsy?
就剩血检报告了
Just a report on the blood work.
血检
Blood work?
天啊
Holy shit.
这太离谱了
This is insane.
谁会为了敲诈我而烧了一整栋楼
I mean, who would blow up a whole real building just to blackmail me?
玛塔  这说明敲诈者手上有
Marta, this means the blackmailer has the only paper copy
唯一一份能证明你有罪的纸质报告
of the thing that can prove your guilt.
你没有收到别的指示吗
You didn't get any other instructions?
没有接到电话  收到电邮之类的吗
No phone call? No email? Nothing?
没有
No.
我还没看过我的电子邮箱
Well, I haven't checked my email.
有一封电邮
There is one.
哥伦比亚路1209号  上午十点
对  这就是了
Yeah, that's it.
"哥伦比亚路1209号  上午十点"
"1209, Columbus Road. 10 a.m."
你知道这意味着什么吧
You know what this means, right?
只要你毁了那份文件
If you destroy that copy,
就完全清白了
you're totally in the clear.
不
Oh, no.
玛塔  你听到了吗
Marta, did you hear me?
听到了
Yeah.
艾略特
Elliott!
快走  快走
We gotta go! We gotta go!
-好了  小车神  -天啊
- Okay, baby driver. - Oh, God.
你后悔帮我了吗
You regret helping me yet?
我后悔没开宝马
I regret not taking the Beemer.
该死
Oh, shit.
来电
疑似贝努瓦·布兰克
-正在华盛顿大街上追击车辆  -别用武力
- Vehicles in pursuit on Washington Street. - No force.
-一定要说"别用武力"  -别用武力
- Make sure you say "No force." - No force.
车上有一位疑似谋杀嫌疑犯
We got a possible murder suspect.
我说了  我说了
I said that. I said that.
快  快  快  油门踩到底了吗
Go. Go! Go! Are you flooring it?
踩到底了
I am literally flooring it!
来电
疑似布兰克·贝努瓦
-真是顺利  -我要停车  我...
- This is going well. - I'm pulling over. I'm...
你要是错过这个拿到毒理学报告的机会
If you miss your chance to get this tox report,
就完蛋了
it's all over.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
为什么  为什么要停下
Why... Why are we stopping?
为什么要停在路中间
Why are you stopping in the middle of the road?
抓紧了
Hold on.
天啊  我现在肾上腺素飙升
Oh, my God, I'm just pure adrenaline right now.
感觉像是吞了蜜蜂
I feel like I swallowed bees.
好了
Okay...
所以是哪里  地址是什么
So where is it? What's the address?
哥伦比亚路1209号
1209, Columbus Road.
好  不管他们要什么
Okay. I mean, whatever they want,
-我都会答应  -任何条件
- I'll say yes... - Anything.
拿回报告就好
You know, just to get that report back.
-拿回来销毁  -销毁它
- Get it back and destroy it. - Destroy it.
天啊  兰森
Holy shit, Ransom.
谢谢你
Hey, thank you.
要是没有你  我肯定做不到
I couldn't do this without you.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
下车
Get out.
这真是有史以来最愚蠢的汽车追逐
That was the dumbest car chase of all time.
把手放下
Put your hands down.
我和曾祖母温娜塔·斯隆贝聊过了
I spoke to Wanetta Thrombey, Greatnana.
派对当晚  她看到有人
Night of the party, she saw someone
顺着棚架爬上了三楼
climbing the trellis to the third floor.
-德莱斯戴尔先生  来  -走吧
- Mr. Drysdale, come on. - Let's go.
对他进行搜身检查
Pat him down, check him out.
怎么回事
What's going on?
她说"兰森回来了"
"Ransom came back," She said.
把手放到车上
Hands on the vehicle.
我不知道他回去干什么
I don't know what he came back to do,
但我们会查出来的
but we'll find out.
你携带着任何利器吗
You got anything sharp?
小心头  谢谢
Watch your head. Thank you.
你不必谢他
Hey, you don't need to thank him.
是他看到我走过去时  让你开车的吗
Did he ask you to drive when he saw me coming?
是的
Yes.
布兰克  跟我们一起走吗
Blanc, coming with us?
我和玛塔一起走
I'll drive with Marta.
去警局吧
Let's go to the police station.
我要详细记录他对你所说的一切
I want a full rundown on everything he said to you.
我会将进展告诉你
I'll catch you up on where we're at.
这案子从一开始就很怪异
Strange case from the start.
案子的中间有个洞
A case with a hole in the middle.
就像甜甜圈
A donut.
我只是在说我的推理过程
I'm just talking through my process here,
你要是觉得无聊就告诉我
let me know if this is boring.
我能感到气氛越来越紧张
I feel the noose tightening.
斯隆贝一家真的很绝望
The family is truly desperate.
绝望的动机
Desperate motives,
雇用我的神秘人
the mystery of who hired me,
犯罪之不可能性
the impossibility of the crime,
而这...
and yet...
就像一个甜甜圈
A donut.
缺失的中心
One central piece
如果它浮出水面  迷雾就会消散
and if it reveals itself, the fog would lift,
就能查明案情  厘清是非
the arc would resolve, the Slinky become unkinked.
哥伦比亚路
单行道
我能停一下吗
Do you mind if I stop for a second?
我要去取个东西
I need to pick something up.
很快的
It'll be very quick.
好的
Sure.
约翰洗衣店
只要几分钟就好
It'll be just a few minutes.
小心...开门
Watch the, uh, door.
约翰洗衣店
后门入口  1209号
有人吗
Hello?
听着  我不知道你想要什么
Listen, I don't know what you want...
不管你想怎样  我们都能解决
Whatever it is, we can work it out.
但必须现在就在这里解决
But we have to figure it out right here, right now.
而且你要把报告交给我
And I'm leaving with that report.
听到了吗
Hello?
弗兰
Fran?
不  不  不  不  弗兰
No, no, no, no! Fran?
天啊  弗兰
Oh, my God, Fran.
你能听见吗
Can you hear me?
弗兰  你要是能听见就示意我
Fran, give me a sign if you can hear me.
-你...  -没错  是我  我是玛塔
- You... - Yes, it's me. It's Marta.
你叫我来这里  给我发了电邮
You called me here, you sent me an email,
所以我来了  你摄入了什么东西吗
that's why I'm here. Did you take something?
我现在叫救护车  你会没事的
I'm gonna call an ambulance now, you're gonna be okay.
吗啡
你会没事的  好吗
You're gonna be fine, okay?
-坚持住  -报告...
- Stay with me. - Copy...
-什么  -报告...
- What? - Copy...
藏起来...
Stashed...
什么  你在说什么
What? What are you saying?
是你干的
You did this.
你逃不掉的
Won't get away with this.
天啊  别说了
Jesus, stop it!
姓名  玛塔·卡布瑞拉
正在呼叫
紧急中心
紧急中心  你有什么紧急情况
911, what's your emergency?
Losing My Mind - Stephen Sondheim
♪ 对你的思念不止 ♪
♪ The thought of you stays bright ♪
♪ 有时我呆立在房间中央 ♪
♪ Sometimes I stand in the middle of the floor ♪
♪ 不向左 ♪
♪ Not going left ♪
♪ 不向... ♪
♪ Not going... ♪
老天啊
Oh, Lord.
好的  朋友  谢谢你及时通知
All right, my friend, thank you for the update.
不用了
No need for that.
一等管家情况稳定
I'll bring her in once we get word
我就带她过去
that the housekeeper is stable.
目前她还没有脱离生命危险
It's still touch and go.
好的
All right.
结束吧
Listen, this is over.
已经有人受到了伤害
People are getting hurt.
所以我会把真相告诉你
So I'm gonna tell you the truth.
兰森刚才对艾略特警官和盘托出了
Young Ransom just told Lieutenant Elliott everything.
挺好
Good.
等等  我希望他没有替我打掩护
Wait, I hope he didn't cover for me.
他有没有向你们坦白全部事实
Did he tell you the real truth
-我搞错药的事...  -说了
- about me switching the... - Yeah.
-变装呢  -说了
- And the disguise bit? - Yes.
还有被勒索和...
And the whole blackmail and...
可是弗兰为什么要拿走我的吗啡
But why did Fran take my morphine?
显然她之前把医疗包从房里偷走了
I mean, obviously she had swiped the bag from the house,
可她看着不像是吗啡上瘾的人
but she didn't seem like a user to me,
除非她就是因此才需要勒索钱财
unless that's why she needed the blackmail money.
不知道  反正这也不重要了
I don't know, it doesn't matter anyway.
我得亲自向斯隆贝一家坦白
I have to tell the Thrombeys myself,
我觉得这是我欠他们的
I feel like I owe that to them.
我可不赞同
I don't think that's a good idea.
不  我得坦白  我需要坦白
No, I have to do it. I need to do it.
我把电话留给医生了
I gave the doctors my number,
如果弗兰这里情况有变  他们会打给我
so they'll call if anything changes with Fran.
好吧
All right.
我会在斯隆贝家召集他们一家人
I'll round up the Thrombeys at the house,
再叫上警察
along with a police escort.
为了之后逮捕我
For the arrest after.
你可以在开车去的路上把整个故事告诉我
You can tell me your whole story on the drive over.
我可不想再有什么"惊喜"了
I don't want any more surprises.
弗兰说她把报告藏起来了
Fran said it was stashed, the copy,
她还说
and then she said,
"是你干的  你逃不掉的"
"You did this. You won't get away with it,"
然后我就叫救护车了
and I called the ambulance.
就这样
That's it.
好的
All right.
准备好了吗
You ready?
来了
Okay.
她想明白了吗
Well, has she come to her senses?
她就站在那  理查德
Well, she's standing right there, Richard,
-她可以自己回答  -家庭成员都来齐了吗
- she can speak for herself. - Is the rest of the family here?
-在客厅  -我觉得我们再聚齐一次
- In the living room. - I think that it would be better
把整件事做个了结比较好
if we were to gather again and get this over with.
真抱歉我和他们说了你妈妈的事
I'm so sorry I told them about your mom.
没关系的  梅格
Meg, it's okay.
对不起  我好怕  我...
I'm sorry. No... I was scared. I just...
我不想说的
I didn't wanna tell them.
我明白
I get it.
相信我
Trust me,
我懂  没事的
I understand. It's all right.
对不起
I'm sorry.
老天  事后我一定要把弗兰的藏货洗劫一空
God, I am so raiding Fran's stash after this.
我仍认为这不是个好主意
I still think this is a bad idea,
不过家庭成员都聚齐了
but the family is assembled.
我知道毒理学报告在哪了
I know where the tox report is.
她等于是直接告诉我了
She basically told me where it was.
毒理学报告
无论如何  这份报告能把真相串连起来
Anyways, this will tie everything up.
而报告我已经交到你手上了
And I just handed it to you.
天啊  你这侦探可真不算高明  不是吗
God, you're not much of a detective, are you?
说句公道话
Well, to be fair,
你这凶手当得也不怎么样
you make a pretty lousy murderer.
也许我俩是绝配
Perhaps we deserve each other.
各位一直对我很好
You've always been good to me.
我接下来要说的事非同小可
And what I'm about to say isn't gonna be easy
你们听了会动怒
and you're gonna be upset.
可是我想  过去这些天
But I thought after what you've gone through
你们经历了那么多纷争
the last few days,
你们理应听我说出真相
that you deserved to hear it from me.
-我...  -打断一下
- I... - Excuse me!
你们哪里对她好了
You have not been good to her.
为了窃回你们已然失去
You have all treated her like shit,
且理应归她的财产
to steal back a fortune that you lost,
你们视她如敝屣
and she deserves.
你们就像一群扑食的饿虎
You're a pack of vultures at the feast!
利刃出鞘  磨牙吮血
Knives out, beaks bloody!
不过
Well,
这一回你们绝不可能全身而退
you're not getting bailed out, not this time.
卡布瑞拉小姐最终决定
Ms. Cabrera has decided, definitively,
不会放弃遗产继承
not to renounce the inheritance.
-什么  -什么
- What? - What?
并且  我会向本地警方提供专业意见
Furthermore, it will be my professional recommendation
表明本案中哈兰·斯隆贝之死
to the local authorities that the manner of death
当以自杀判定
in the case of Harlan Thrombey is ruled as suicide!
-结案  -布兰克
- And the case is closed. - Blanc?
什么
What?
感谢各位前来  再见
Thank you all for coming. Goodbye.
什么情况  你告诉我...
What's going on? Just tell me...
这显然不是我所期待的结局
That's certainly not what I was expecting.
不
No.
还有人和我一样糊涂吗
Is anybody else confused?
我可一点都不想听到这个结局
Not what I was expecting to hear at all.
你是不是该告诉我到底什么情况
Are you gonna tell me what the hell is going on?
是  是
Yes. Yes.
我只想澄清真相  好吗
I just wanna come clean, okay?
-都结束了  -快结束了
- It's over. - Almost.
布兰克  你在干什么
Blanc, what are we doing?
-这是怎么了  -抱歉  瓦格纳警员
- What's going on? - I'm sorry. Officer Wagner.
别让这家人进这个房间
Keep the family out of this room,
如果可以的话  直接赶出这座房子
and get 'em out of the house if you can.
但是你和你的随行警员要随时待命
But stand by with your additional officer.
把这家人赶走
Get the family out?
对  不过别全都赶走  拜托你...
Yes, but not all of them. Would you...
谢谢
Thank you.
-布兰克  -是  先生
- Blanc... - Yes, sir.
差不多行了  你葫芦里卖的什么药
Come on, come on, what's all this drama?
-容我把话说完  -布兰克
- Indulge me. - Blanc,
我都告诉兰森了  兰森也告诉你们了
I told Ransom, Ransom told you,
我现在跟你们说清楚
and I'm telling you now,
是我杀了哈兰  无可辩驳
it is an immovable fact that I killed Harlan.
你是说了  他也说了  你说得很清楚
Yes, you did, yes, he did, yes, you are.
但是  我在车里提到过
But... But, I spoke in the car about the hole
甜甜圈中心的那个洞
at the center of this donut.
你和哈兰在案发当晚的所作所为
And what you and Harlan did that fateful night
乍看之下似乎完美地填补了那个洞
seems at first glance to fill that hole perfectly.
甜甜圈洞里甜甜圈球
A donut hole in a donut's hole.
但我们得凑近了观察
But we must look a little closer.
那时我们就会发现甜甜圈球的中心
And when we do, we see the donut hole
还有一个洞
has a hole in its center.
那并不是甜甜圈球
It is not a donut hole,
而是一个小号的甜甜圈  以及中心的洞
but a smaller donut with its own hole
这样原本的大甜甜圈根本就不完整
and our donut is not whole at all!
布兰克  我知道你觉得这么兜圈子有意思
Blanc, look, I understand that this is amusing for you...
为什么要雇用我
Why was I hired?
为什么有人要雇用我
Why would someone hire me?
有人想要证明发生了犯罪行为
Someone fishing for a crime
从而撤销遗嘱  布兰克  行了
to reverse the will, Blanc. Come on.
但我在遗嘱拆封前就被雇用了
But I was hired before the sealed will was read.
所以  没错
So, yes,
这个人一定早就知道遗嘱的内容
the person must have known the contents of the will.
可是再往下想
But one step further,
这个人一定还早就知道有人犯了罪
that same person must have known a crime was committed,
再往下想...
and further...
如果对方的意图是撤销玛塔的继承权
If the intent was to reverse Marta's inheritance,
对方一定早就知道玛塔就是罪魁祸首
they must have known that Marta was responsible.
引人入胜而又环环相扣的线索
An intriguing combination of factors.
有人知道玛塔做了什么
Someone who knew what Marta did
想揭发她
wanted to expose it
但却不能暴露自己是如何得知的
but could not reveal how they knew.
是弗兰
Fran!
她勒索了我  她知道我做了什么
She was blackmailing me. She knew what I did.
没错  可是弗兰想要的是钱
Yeah, but Fran wanted money,
所以她并不希望罪行曝光
ergo she did not want the crime exposed.
如果这家人里有谁看到了
What if someone in the family had observed
玛塔有可疑举动呢
Marta doing something suspicious?
但他们没有理由缄口不言
But they would have had no reason not to speak up.
答案没有这么简单
The answer is not so simple.
现在我已然看穿了全部真相
Now with the entire solution in my field of view,
这背后的故事是一系列错误导致的悲剧
the arc of this case is a tragedy of errors.
玛塔  这话可能会让你难以接受
Marta, it will not be easy for you to hear.
但这背后
But there is at least
至少有一个幕后黑手
one truly guilty party behind it all,
一个怀着真正恶意
guilty in the true sense of acting with malice
为了一己私利犯下滔天罪行的幕后黑手
and committing a heinous crime with selfish intent.
瓦格纳警员
Trooper Wagner.
凶手是瓦格纳警员
Trooper Wagner?
不是
No.
玛塔  对不起  我把一切都告诉他们了
Marta, I'm so sorry. I told them everything.
我以为一切都结束了  对不起
I figured it was up. I'm sorry.
没事的  兰森  我很高兴你说出来了
Hey. It's all right, Ransom, I'm glad you did.
可他并没说出全部
Not exactly everything though.
你在怀疑曾祖母和你说的话吗
Is this about what Greatnana told you?
那晚她看到的是我  她把我认成兰森了
She saw me that night. She mistook me for Ransom.
这个我们后面再说
We'll get to that.
与此同时
In the meanwhile,
休·兰森·德莱斯戴尔先生
Mr. Hugh Ransom Drysdale,
你不妨告诉大家  你为什么要雇用我
you might tell us all why you hired me.
我为什么要雇用你
Why I hired you?
你说得对  我们来复盘一下
You're right, let's back it up...
回到派对那一晚
To the night of the party.
你和哈兰发生的争执
Your argument with Harlan.
在洗手间自慰的纳粹小子
What were the overheard words
听到了什么来着
by the Nazi child masturbating in the bathroom?
"我的遗嘱"  还有"我警告你"
"My will," and "I'm warning you."
你和哈兰都喜欢看好戏
You and Harlan were drama mamas,
你俩都十分享受慢慢折磨对方
you shared a love of twisting the knife into one another.
所以  我不相信
You see, I don't believe
他会说到一半突然转移话题
he would have slipped it in halfway,
不  不  肯定不会
no, no, no.
我认为
I submit
哈兰告诉了你一切
Harlan told you everything.
你开什么玩笑
You can't be serious!
他们谁都别想拿到
Not a red dime or word of my work
我的一本书  一毛钱  包括你
to a single one of them, you included.
玛塔
Marta,
提醒我一下  兰森说
remind me what Ransom said
他和哈兰的对话是如何结束的
his conversation with Harlan ended with?
哈兰对他说我下围棋能打败他
Harlan told him that I could beat him at Go.
我问自己
And I asked myself,
"玛塔
"Marta?
为什么关于遗嘱的话题
Why would the topic of the will
会绕到玛塔那去"
Have steered around to Marta?"
只有一个显而易见的解释
There is one obvious explanation...
你不至于那么疯狂
You can't be that crazy.
你不会就那么把全副身家都抛弃了
You're not just gonna throw away your fortune.
当然不会  我会把一切都留给玛塔
No. I'm giving it to Marta.
所有财产
All of it.
你的巴西护士
Your Brazilian nurse?
你他妈的是疯了吗
Are you goddamn insane?
我一生中第一次这么理智
I'm sane for the first time in my life,
而且我已经改好了
and I've done it.
哈兰  如果你认为我会让这发生
Harlan, if you think I'm gonna let this happen,
我会坐以待毙...
if you think I'm gonna stand here and...
我已经改好了遗嘱  木已成舟
I've made the change to my will. It's done.
我警告你
I'm warning you!
你这可是很严重的指控
That's some heavy-duty conjecture.
可以这么说
Granted.
但只有这么解释  接下来发生的事才说得通
But it is the only way what comes next makes sense.
你气冲冲地离开  深夜驾车离去
So you storm out, you drive off into the night.
你后来对玛塔说
You tell Marta later...
什么来着  感到了前所未有的...
What was it? Feeling an overwhelming sense of...
清明
Clarity.
说从那以后他要为自己盘算
That he had to make do for himself from here on out.
没错
Exactly.
玛塔  遗嘱  哈兰
Marta. The will. Harlan.
"为自己盘算"
"Do for yourself."
"你逃不掉的"
"You won't get away with this."
你心里有了计划
And a plan forms.
你回到庄园
You return,
小心地避开了门口的监控摄像头
careful to avoid the gate's security camera range.
然后步行走向房子
Then on foot up towards the house,
你沿着棚架偷偷爬进屋
you sneak in up the trellis,
这样就不会被仍然在楼下开派对的
so as not to be seen by the rest of the family
其余家人发现
who are still having their party downstairs.
你想要做的只需片刻即可
What you need to do will take moments.
但你必须只身一人不被发现  这至关重要
But it is essential that you are alone and undetected.
你知道哈兰所使用的药物
You knew what medications Harlan took.
你知道那晚玛塔会给他注射什么
You knew what Marta would be injecting him with that night.
吗啡  痛立消
而且你知道
And you knew
如果他因为玛塔而死
if Marta was responsible for his death,
即便是无心之失
even unintentionally,
凶手规则将会使更改后的遗嘱失效
the slayer rule would nullify the changed will
而你将会拿回你的那份财产
and you would get your share back.
你使用药箱里的注射器
You used the syringes in the kit
吗啡
将两个药瓶里的液体调换了
to switch the liquids in the two medication vials.
而且  为了保险起见
And as a final precaution...
痛立消
你拿走了纳洛酮
you took the Naloxone,
能够救命的解毒剂
the lifesaving antidote.
不  不不不  这不可能
No. No, no, no, that's impossible.
这就是真相
That is the truth.
把那瓶吗啡递给我  我证明给你看
Hand me that vial of morphine, I'll show you.
如果他那么做了  如果药被调换了
If he did that, if the meds were switched,
那么当我把它们搞混的时候  我...
then when I got them mixed up, I...
我就意外地又将它们调换回来了
I accidentally switched them back,
那么我给哈兰注射的是...
so I gave Harlan...
正确的剂量
The correct doses.
是的
Yes.
但那并不是意外
But not accidentally.
我将这两瓶药的标签遮盖掉了
I taped over the label of these two vials.
这两个瓶子是完全一样的
The vials themselves are identical.
吗啡
你怎么知道这瓶是吗啡
How'd you know this was the morphine?
我就是知道
I just knew.
你能分辨  是因为
You knew because there is the slightest,
这两种液体的色泽和黏度
almost imperceptible differences
有着几乎无法被察觉的区别
of tincture and viscosity between the two liquids.
你能分辨  是因为你已操作过上百次
You knew because you've done it a hundred times.
你给他注射了正确的药物
You gave him the correct medication
因为你是一个好护士
because you are a good nurse.
那么哈兰...
Then Harlan was...
我很抱歉  玛塔  但是的
I'm sorry, Marta. But yes.
-哈兰当时根本没事  -我的天啊
- Harlan was perfectly fine. - Oh, my God.
他的血检结果是正常的
His blood was normal.
他的死因就是单纯的自杀
The cause of death was truly, solely suicide,
而你完全无罪
and you are guilty of nothing
除了给棚架造成了些破坏
but some damage to the trellis
以及几场业余拙劣的表演
and a few amateur theatrics.
事实上  如果哈兰听了你的话
In fact, if Harlan had listened to you
打电话叫了救护车
and called the ambulance,
他就不会死
he would be alive today.
我靠
Damn!
这是一张错综交织的网
A twisted web
而我们还未将其解开
and we are not finished untangling it.
还未完全解开
Not yet.
玛塔  当曾祖母发现你
Marta, when Greatnana spotted you
从棚架上往下爬的时候  她说..
climbing down the trellis, she said...
兰森  你又回来了吗
Ransom? Are you back again already?
她说"你又回来了吗"
"Are you back again already?"
因为那晚早些时候
'Cause earlier that night...
兰森  你回来了
Ransom, you're back?
拜托  玛塔
Come on, Marta.
这说法真是愚蠢到家了
This is stoopid with two o's.
你一丁点证据都没有
You don't have a shred of evidence,
都是你天方夜谭的想象罢了
you're just spinning a fairy tale.
一丁点都没有  确实
Not a shred, no.
就好比没有确凿的证据证明玛塔弄混了两瓶药
Just as we have no real proof of Marta mixing up the vials,
所以各执...
so it's your word...
她都认罪了
You have her confession!
也对  确实
All right, yeah.
我们确实有她的供词
Yeah, we do have that.
如果可以
With your permission,
我想再多想象一些
I'd like to spin a little further.
那晚更晚的时候
Much later that night,
你不得不回到房子里
you'd have to come back to the house...
取走作为罪证的动过手脚的药瓶
to retrieve the incriminating tampered vials.
然而  这回狗出来了
However, this time the dogs were outside.
他们狂吠  吵醒了梅格
They barked, waking Meg.
没关系
No matter.
你可以明天再拿药瓶
You'll get the vials tomorrow.
但是  第二天见报的新闻
But tomorrow brings news...
不是医疗事故和有罪的护士
Not of a medical error and a guilty nurse,
而是割喉自杀
but of a slit throat and a suicide.
著名作家斯隆贝享年85岁
现在是匿名雇用我的
Now the circumstances are perfect
最佳时机
for the anonymous hirin' of me.
你知道卡布瑞拉小姐犯了罪
You know a crime has been committed by Miss Cabrera,
绅士侦探
你需要她被捉拿归案
you need her to be caught for it.
你不能泄露你是如何知道的
You cannot reveal how you know.
下面登场的是
Enter...
贝努瓦·布兰克
Benoit Blanc.
贝尼
Benny, look...
我听懂你的推断了  但是...
I hear what you're saying, but this...
尸体在第二天大清早就被发现了
The body is discovered early the next morning.
警察  法医  家人
The police, the medical examiner, the family,
所有人蜂拥而至
everyone swarms in
犯罪现场  请止步
你根本没可能
and there is no possible way
从玛塔的医疗包里
you can get to Marta's medical bag
取回药瓶
to retrieve the vials.
你必须等待时机
You must wait for your moment,
等调查结束
when the investigation is over
等你确定房子里空无一人的时候
and you know the house will be empty.
所以你才
And that is why
没有参加葬礼
you missed the funeral.
家里一个人也没有
There is no one home
你就能神不知鬼不觉地去哈兰的书房
to wonder why you're going into Harlan's study.
但人算不如天算
Or so you think.
可怜的弗兰
Poor Fran.
她亲眼看到你在对
She witnessed you tampering
医疗包里哈兰的药物动手脚
with Harlan's medication in the medical bag.
她当时不知道你在做什么
She did not know what you were doing.
但她知道你一定没安好心
But she knew you were up to no good.
所以她开始对你产生怀疑
So her mind begins to turn.
天啊
Oh, God.
她跟我提到的那部贺曼公司的电影
That Hallmark movie she told me about,
丹妮卡·麦凯拉主演的...
with Danica McKellar...
《意外致死》
Deadly by Surprise.
原来她是指这件事
That's what she was talking about.
她爱哈兰
She loved Harlan.
但是恨兰森
She hates Ransom.
所以这个可怜的姑娘决定去证实她的猜想
So the poor girl decides to test her theory,
让这个混蛋付出代价
and make this asshole pay.
她设法拿到了一份毒理学检测报告
She gets a copy of the toxicology report.
说实话  我不知道她怎么做到的
Now, I will be honest, I have no idea how.
她有个表妹
'Cause she has a cousin.
她跟我说过  她有个表妹
She told me, she has a cousin
在法医办公室当接待员
who works as a receptionist at the examiner's office.
那就说得通了
Well, voila!
她其实对表上的数字一窍不通
The numbers, they mean nothing to her,
但如果兰森有罪
but if Ransom is guilty,
这份报告就能对他构成威胁
its existence is a threat
所以她复印了报告的开头  写下了勒索信
so she photocopies the header and makes her blackmail note.
那她为什么寄给我
So why did she send it to me?
她没有
She didn't.
她寄给的是兰森
She sent it to Ransom.
你猜德莱斯戴尔先生收到信时
And when Mr. Drysdale gets it,
他是什么反应
what is his reaction?
得意洋洋
Elation.
他还误以为玛塔给哈兰注射了调包后的药物
He still thinks Marta has given Harlan the tampered drugs.
这份血检报告能证明她有罪
A blood tox report will prove her guilt.
所以他满心欢喜地去听了遗嘱宣读
He goes to the will reading in high spirits,
准备欣赏一家人分崩离析的好戏
ready to see the family tear itself apart,
因为他确信一旦血检报告公开
secure in the knowledge it will be all undone
这一切都会全部作废
when the tox report comes to light.
但紧接着...
And then...
玛塔坦白
Marta's confession.
事态扭转
And everything turns on its head.
他此时意识到玛塔并没有犯罪
He now realizes that Marta has committed no crime
而血检报告恰好能证明她的清白
and the tox report will prove her innocence.
修改后的遗嘱依旧有效
The changed will is gonna stand.
他一时慌了神
He has lost.
除非...
Unless...
除非你决定...
Unless you decide...
你不会放弃遗产
You're not gonna give up the money.
你都走到这一步了
You've come this far.
只要再往前走一步
Just one step further,
最后再行动一次
just one last act.
一不做  二不休
In for a penny, in for a pound.
你索性做到底
You decide you are in.
第一步
Step one...
销毁所有能证明玛塔清白的证据
Destroy all evidence of Marta's innocence.
第二步
Step two,
向她发送匿名邮件
send her the anonymous email
哥伦比亚路1209号  上午十点
约她上午见面
with a late morning rendezvous time...
哥伦比亚路1209号  早上八点
然后亲自把勒索信送到她家里
And deliver her the blackmail note.
第三步
Step three,
早上赴弗兰之约
keep your appointment with Fran.
我就知道
I knew it.
我就知道你是个图谋不轨的王八蛋
I knew you were a no-good son of a bitch.
我就知道哈兰不会平白无故地自杀
I knew Harlan wouldn't just kill himself.
没错  弗兰  你说得对
Yes, Fran, you were right.
我就知道你就是凶手
I knew you were guilty as shit.
而现在你要为此付出代价
And now you're gonna pay for it!
你胆敢过来
Don't you come near me.
别过来  我警告你
Don't come near me! I'm warning you!
现在局已设好
See, now, now the board is set.
毒理学检测报告
玛塔会收到勒索信
Marta will get the blackmail note.
你负责帮她拼凑线索
You'll put the pieces together for her.
你会引导她到会面点
You'll guide her to the rendezvous.
再匿名报警
You'll make the anonymous call to the police,
警方会在现场抓她个正着
they will catch her there
连带着尸体和烧毁的证据一起
with the body and the burned evidence.
玛塔会因谋杀弗兰和哈兰而被逮捕
Marta will get arrested for killing Fran and Harlan.
她说
She said...
是你干的
You did this.
她说的不是
She didn't say...
"是你干的"
"You did this."
她不是指我  她说的是
She wasn't talking about me, she said...
是休干的
Hugh did this.
"是休干的"
"Hugh did this."
因为你让佣人都叫你休
'Cause you made the help call you Hugh.
因为你就是个混蛋
'Cause you're an asshole.
这计划本该奏效
And it would have worked
但我们阴差阳错地把你抓进警局审问
if we hadn't have brought you in for questioning
导致你没法打匿名电话报警
so you could not make your anonymous call.
加之弗兰还藏了一份
And if Fran had not stashed
血检报告以防万一
a safety copy of the tox report.
玛塔也再次坏了你的好事
And if Marta had not outplayed you once again.
因为她心地善良
By having a kind heart.
救了弗兰一命
By saving Fran's life
即便这会让她失去遗产
though it meant her losing the inheritance
锒铛入狱
and going to jail.
她没有陷入你的圈套
She didn't play your game.
她救了弗兰的命
She saved Fran's life.
弗兰还活着
Fran's alive?
是的
Yes.
弗兰
Fran...
她能证实这一推测
who will confirm this very story
来电
克利夫顿医院
至少八九不离十
or something close to it.
然后让你  休
And send you, Hugh,
进监狱
to jail.
你好
Yes?
医生  这真是太好了
Doctor, that's great news.
我们马上过去  谢谢
We'll be there soon. Thank you.
她没事
She's okay.
她准备好录口供了
She's ready to talk.
瓦格纳警员  麻烦你
Trooper Wagner, if you could,
把德莱斯戴尔先生铐起来
keep Mr. Drysdale in custody
而艾略特警督  卡布瑞拉女士和我
while Lieutenant Elliott, Ms. Cabrera and myself,
会去医院给弗兰录口供
we go to the hospital and take Fran's statement.
好了  快站起来
All right. Up, come on.
这话我只会当面对你说
I'm gonna say this just to you.
这里没有监控  也不是法院
No cameras, no courtroom,
只有你  因为知道我说的是实话
just you, 'cause you know it's true.
我们让你进了我们家门
We allowed you into our home.
让你照看我们的爷爷
We let you watch our granddad,
欢迎你融入我们的大家庭
we welcomed you into our family.
你现在还真以为能从我们手里夺走遗产
And now you think you can steal it from us?
你以为我不会奋起反抗保护我的家
You think I'm not gonna fight to protect my home,
我们的继承权
our birthright,
还有我们代代相传的祖屋吗
our ancestral family home?
别胡说八道了
That is hooey.
这栋房子是哈兰上世纪八十年代
Harlan, he bought this place in the '80s
从一个巴基斯坦房地产富豪那里买下的
from a Pakistani real estate billionaire.
闭嘴  布兰克  给我闭嘴
Shut up, Blanc! Shut up!
收起你那油嘴滑舌拖着调子的南方乡巴佬腔
Shut up with that Kentucky Fried Foghorn Leghorn drawl!
没错  我试图杀了弗兰  但好像没成功
Yeah, I killed Fran. But I guess I didn't.
你们是有我什么证据吗
So what do you have on me?
什么都没有  所以最多判个谋杀未遂
Nothing. What, attempted murder?
烧房子判个纵火罪  再加上其他几项罪名
I get arson for the building, and a few other charges.
只要找个好律师  恰好我有
With a good lawyer, which I have,
我用不了多久就能出狱
I'll be out in no time.
到时候你就等着看
And then you'll see
我会让你有多么生不如死
just how much hell I can wreak on your life,
你这个恶毒的贱婊子
you vicious little bitch.
搞毛啊
What the shit!
这说明她说谎了
That means she's lying!
不用你多嘴  我们知道
Yeah, man, we know.
没错
That's right.
弗兰死了
Fran's dead.
而你刚刚承认杀了她
And you just confessed to her murder.
好吧
Well...
那就不做不休
In for a penny...
靠
Shit.
我的宝贝
是时候离开他了  他在背着你偷腥
我手里有证据  但我知道你不用看
尽早抽身  是时候了
爸爸
琳达
Linda!
我们得马上给律师打电话
We've gotta get the attorneys on the phone right now!
我们...
We...
我能不能问问
Can I ask
你是什么时候知道我跟哈兰的死有关的
when did you know I had something to do with Harlan's death?
你第一次走到我面前的时候就知道了
From the first moment you set foot in front of me.
该死
Shit.
我想让你记住一件事
I want you to remember something
非常重要
that's very important.
你之所以能赢
You won,
不是靠哈兰给你指的路
not by playing the game Harlan's way,
而是靠你自己
but yours.
你是个好人
You're a good person.
他们一家
This family.
我应该帮助他们  对吗
I should help them. Right?
我可没这么想
Well, I have my opinion,
不过我有预感你会遵从自己的内心
but I have a feeling you'll follow your heart.
我的房子
我的规则
我的咖啡
利刃出鞘